第一章
Chapter One
很久以前...
Once upon a time...
在纳粹占领的法国
in Nazi-occupied France
1941年
进去，把门关上
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Go back inside and shut the door.
茱莉，替我装盆水洗脸...
Julie, get me some water
for my wash up...
...然后进屋子去
...then get inside with your sisters.
拿去，爸爸
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Ready, Papa.
谢谢你，乖女儿...
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Thank you, my darling...
...现在进去陪你姐姐
...now you go inside with your sisters.
不要跑
Don't run.
这是皮瑞拉帕帝的家吗？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
ls this the property of Perrier LaPadite?
我就是皮瑞拉帕帝
l am Perrier LaPadite.
幸会了，拉帕帝先生...
lt is a pleasure to meet you,
Monsieur LaPadite...
...我是纳粹党卫军汉斯蓝达上校
...l am Colonel Hans Landa of the SS.
我能为你做什么？
What can l do for you?
请我进去你家...
l was hoping you could invite me
inside your home...
...咱们俩一起谈谈
...and we may have a discussion.
没问题，请吧
Certainly. After you.
蓝达上校，这是我的家人
Colonel Landa, this is my family.
我是纳粹党卫军汉斯蓝达上校...
Colonel Hans Landa of the SS...
...小姐们...
...Mademoiselle...
...我随时效劳
...at your service.
关于你们家的谣言是真的
The rumors l have heard in the
village about your family are all true.
你的女儿一个比一个漂亮
Each one of your daughters
is more lovely than the last.
谢谢
Merci.
来...
Please...
...请坐
...have a seat.
苏珊，替上校倒杯酒
Suzanne, would you be so good as to
get the Colonel some wine?
不
But no.
谢谢你，但是我不喝酒
Merci beaucoup, Monsieur LaPadite,
but no wine.
这是酪农场
你家应该有牛奶吧？
This being a dairy farm, one would be
safe in assuming you have milk?
对
Oui.
那就来杯牛奶吧
Then milk is what l prefer.
好的
Very well.
茱莉，请你关上窗户
Julie, would you mind closing the window?
谢谢你
Merci.
我要对你家人和你的乳牛...
Monsieur, to both your family
and your cows...
...说声：  “好极了”
...l say, ''Bravo.''
谢谢你
Thank you.
一起过来坐
Please Join me at your table.
好的
Very well.
拉帕帝先生...
Monsieur LaPadite...
...我们要谈的事最好私下谈
...what we have to discuss
would be better discussed in private.
我请手下在外面等
You'll notice l left my men outdoors.
不介意的话，请小姐们出去
lf it wouldn't offend them, could you
ask your lovely ladies to step outside?
说得对
You are right.
夏绿蒂，带她们出去
Charlotte, would you take the girls
outside?
我和上校有话要谈
The Colonel and l need to have
a few words.
拉帕帝先生...
Monsieur LaPadite...
...很抱歉，我会的法文都讲光了
...l regret to inform you
l've exhausted the extent of my French.
勉强讲下去只会让我很糗
To continue to speak it so inadequately
would only serve to embarrass me.
但是听说你的英文说得很溜
However, l've been led to believe
you speak English quite well.
是的
Yes.
我也是，那么客随主便...
Well, it Just so happens, l do as well.
This being your house...
...请你让我用英文继续说下去
...l ask your permission to switch
to English...
...for the remainder of the conversation.
请便
By all means.
我对你和你家人很熟悉
While l'm very familiar
with you and your family,
但我不知道你对我熟不熟悉
l have no way of knowing
if you are familiar with who l am.
你知道有我这个人吗？
Are you aware of my existence?
-知道
-非常好
-Yes.
-This is good.
你知道我在法国的任务吗？
Now, are you aware of the Job l've been
ordered to carry out in France?
知道
Yes.
请告诉我你听说什么
Please tell me what you've heard.
我听说元首命令你捕杀
仍在法国的犹太人
l've heard
that the Fuhrer has put you in charge
of rounding up the Jews left in France
他们不是躲起来
就是假装成非犹太人
who are either hiding or passing for Gentile.
就连元首都没你说得好
The Fuhrer couldn't have
said it better himself.
虽然我很欢迎你来访
But the meaning of your visit,
但是却不知道原因
pleasant though it is, is mysterious to me.
德军九个月前来搜过我家
The Germans looked through my house
nine months ago for hiding Jews
什么也没找到
and found nothing.
我知道
l'm aware of that.
我看过报告
l've read the reports of this area.
但是就像每个新官上任的公司
But like any enterprise,
when under new management,
同样的事得再做一次
there is always
a slight duplication of efforts,
大部分是浪费时间
但还是非做不可
most of it being a complete waste of time,
but needs to be done nevertheless.
我只想请教一些问题
l Just have a few questions,
monSieur LaPadite.
你只要照实回答
lf you can assist me with answers,
你家的档案就能结案
my department can close
the file on your family.
是这样的
Now,
法国被占领之前
这地区有四家犹太人
before the occupation,
there were four Jewish families in this area,
全都跟你一样是酪农
all dairy farmers like yourself.
德勒列克、罗伦昂、拉维特
Doleracs, Rollins, the Loveitts
以及德瑞芙斯
and the Dreyfuses.
对吧？
ls that correct?
就我所知
To my knowledge,
他们是犹太裔的酪农
those were the Jewish families
among the dairy farmers.
上校，介意我抽烟斗吗？
Herr Colonel,
would it disturb you if l smoked my pipe?
请便，拉帕帝先生
(CHUCKLES) Please,
monSieur LaPadite,
这是你家，自在一点
this is your house,
make yourself comfortable.
根据这些文件
Now, according to these papers,
这地区的犹太家庭都被拘捕
all the Jewish families
in this area have been accounted for
除了德瑞芙斯一家人
except the Dreyfuses.
看来他们去年突然消失无踪
Somewhere in the last year
it would appear they've vanished.
我猜他们不是逃亡成功
Which leads me to the conclusion
that they've either made good their escape
就是有人把他们藏得很好
or someone
is very successfully hiding them.
你听过德瑞芙斯一家的事吗？
What have you heard about
the Dreyfuses, monSieur LaPadite?
-只有谣言
-我最爱谣言了！
-Only rumors.
-l love rumors!
事实很容易误导我们
Facts could be so misleading,
谣言不管真假都能泄密
where rumors, true or false,
are often revealing.
所以，拉帕帝先生
So, monSieur LaPadite,
你听过德瑞芙斯一家什么谣言？
what rumors have you heard
regarding the Dreyfuses?
我说过，这只是个谣言
Again, this is Just a rumor,
我们听说德瑞芙斯一家
逃到西班牙了
but we heard the Dreyfuses
had made their way into Spain.
你听到他们逃亡的谣言？
So, the rumors you've heard
have been of escape?
对
Yes.
虽然你没见过德瑞芙斯一家
Having never met the Dreyfuses,
would you confirm for me
但是请你说出他们全家的名字
the exact members of the household
and their names?
他们家有五个人
There were five of them.
父亲，雅各
The father, Jacob.
太太，米兰
Wife, Miram.
还有她的兄弟
巴布
And her brother, Bob.
巴布几岁？
How old is Bob?
30、31岁
Thirty, 31 .
继续说
Continue.
孩子们
And the children,
艾莫斯
Amos
还有苏珊娜
and Shosanna.
孩子们几岁？
Ages of the children?
艾莫斯，9或10岁
Amos was nine or 10.
-苏珊娜呢？
-苏珊娜是
-And Shosanna?
-And Shosanna was
18或19岁
我不是很确定
18 or 19. l'm not really sure.
我猜我问完了
Well, l guess that should do it.
不过我走之前
能不能再来杯好喝的牛奶？
However, before l go, could l have
another glass of your delicious milk?
当然可以
But of course.
拉帕帝先生
MonSieur LaPadite,
你知道法国人替我取的绰号吗？
are you aware of the nickname
the people of France have given me?
我对这种事没兴趣
l have no interest in such things.
但是你知道他们怎么叫我
But you are aware of what they call me.
我知道
l'm aware.
你知道什么？
What are you aware of?
-他们叫你“犹太人终结者”
-没错
-That they call you ''The Jew Hunter.''
-Precisely.
我了解你很怕说出这个绰号
l understand your trepidation in repeating it.
海德利希很讨厌
Heydrich apparently hates the moniker
布拉格人替他取的绰号
the good people of Prague
have bestowed on him.
但是我不t他怎么会讨厌
“刽子手”这绰号
Actually, why he would hate the name
''the Hangman'' is baffling to me.
这绰号一定是他尽全力得到的
lt would appear he has done
everything in his power to earn it.
我不同，我特爱我的绰号
Now l, on the other hand,
love my unofficial title
尤其是我努力挣来的
precisely because l've earned it.
这代表跟其他德国军人比起来
The feature that makes me
such an effective hunter of the Jews is,
我猎杀犹太人的效率超高
as opposed to most German soldiers,
我会像犹太人思考
l can think like a Jew
他们只会像德国人思考
where they can only think like a German.
更精准地说，是德国士兵
(CHUCKLlNG) More precisely,
a German soldier.
若要以一种动物形容德国人
Now, if one were to determine what attribute
the German people share with a beast,
那就是狡猾掠杀的隼鹰
it would be the cunning
and the predatory instinct of a hawk.
若要以一种动物形容犹太人
But if one were to determine what attributes
the Jews share with a beast,
那就是老鼠
it would be that of the rat.
元首和戈培尔的宣传部
也这么形容犹太人
The Fuhrer and Goebbels' propaganda
have said pretty much the same thing.
但是我们的结论不同
But where our conclusions differ,
我不认为比较两者是种羞辱
is l don't consider the comparison an insult.
想一想老鼠生活的世界
Consider for a moment
the world a rat lives in.
那是充满敌意的世界
lt's a hostile world, indeed.
假设现在有只老鼠从门前窜过
lf a rat were to scamper
through your front door, right now,
你会对它有敌意吗？
would you greet it with hostility?
我猜会吧
l suppose l would.
老鼠曾经做了什么
让你对它们充满敌意？
Has a rat ever done anything to you to create
this animosity you feel toward them?
老鼠会散布疾病，还会咬人
Rats spread disease. They bite people.
老鼠的确散播过瘟疫
不过那是很久以前的事
Rats were the cause of the bubonic plague,
but that's some time ago.
让我告诉你
松鼠也能散布老鼠散布的疾病
l propose to you any disease
a rat could spread,
a squirrel could equally carry.
你同意吗？
Would you agree?
但是你对松鼠却没有
Yet, l assume you don't share
the same animosity with squirrels
-对老鼠的敌意，对吧？
-对
-that you do with rats, do you?
-No.
但它们都是啮齿动物呀
Yet, they're both rodents, are they not?
除了尾巴，它们长得挺像的
And except for the tail,
they even rather look alike, don't they?
这想法真有趣，上校
lt's an interesting thought, Herr Colonel.
不管这想法是多么有趣
However interesting as the thought may be,
你对老鼠的看法不会不一样
it makes not one bit of difference
to how you feel.
要是有一只老鼠跑进来
lf a rat were to walk in here, right now,
as l'm talking
你会替它准备一碟牛奶吗？
would you greet it with a saucer
of your delicious milk?
大概不会吧
Probably not.
我就知道
l didn't think so.
你不喜欢老鼠
You don't like them.
你连为什么不喜欢都不知道
You don't really know
why you don't like them.
只知道你觉得老鼠很恶心
All you know is you find them repulsive.
所以说
一名德国士兵前往一个
Consequently, a German soldier
conducts a search
疑似藏匿犹太人的家里搜查
of a house suspected of hiding Jews.
一只隼鹰会从何找起？
Where does the hawk look?
他会搜查谷仓、阁楼、地窖
He looks in the barn, he looks in the attic,
he looks in the cellar,
什么地方他都会仔细搜查
he looks everywhere he would hide.
但有很多藏匿地方隼鹰想不到
But there are so many places
it would never occur to a hawk to hide.
所以元首才会从奥地利
However, the reason the Fuhrer
has brought me off my Alps in Austria
派我到法国的乳牛农场
因为我想得到
and placed me in French cow country today
is because it does occur to me.
因为我知道人一旦放弃尊严
Because l'm aware what tremendous feats
human beings are capable of
会做出多么惊人的举动
once they abandon dignity.
我能抽我的烟斗吗？
May l smoke my pipe as well?
请便，把这里当自己家
Please, Herr Colonel, make yourself at home.
现在呢
我的任务就是
Now, my Job dictates
派我的手下进来你家
that l must have my men enter your home
进行仔细地搜查
and conduct a thorough search
然后才能正式把你从名单删掉
before l can officially cross
your family's name off my list.
要是发现任何异状
然而一定会的
And if there are any irregularities
to be found, rest assured they will be.
除非你跟我实话实说
That is unless you have something to tell me
这样一来就不必搜你家了
that makes the conducting
of a search unnecessary.
我要强调，只要你让我
l might add, also, that any information
轻松完成我的任务就不会受罚
that makes the performance of my duty
easier will not be met with punishment.
恰好相反，你会受到奖赏
Actually, quite the contrary.
lt will be met with reward.
那就是在我们占领法国期间
And that reward will be,
your family will cease
to be harassed in any way
你的家人不会再受到德军骚扰
by the German military during the rest
of our occupation of your country.
你藏匿了德国公敌，对吧？
You're sheltering enemies of the state,
are you not?
对
Yes.
你把他们藏在地板下面？
You're sheltering them underneath
your floorboards, aren't you?
对
Yes.
指出他们藏匿的地方
Point out to me the areas
where they're hiding.
我没听见任何骚动
Since l haven't heard any disturbance,
这表示他们听不懂英文
l assume, while they're listening,
they don't speak English.
是的
Yes.
我要再说法文，跟我演下去
l'm going to switch back to French now,
and l want you to follow my masquerade.
明白吗？
ls that clear?
(SNlFFLES)
明白
Yes.
拉帕帝先生...
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Monsieur LaPadite...
...谢谢你请我喝牛奶...
...l thank you for the milk...
...和你的热情招待
...and your hospitality.
我们的事情已经谈完了
l do believe our business here is done.
小姐们
Ah, ladies.
谢谢你们耐心等待
l thank you for your time.
我们不会再麻烦你们了
We shan't be bothering your family
any longer.
先生...
So, Monsieur...
...小姐们
...Mademoiselle.
让我向你们道别并说声...
l bid farewell to you and say...
...再会
...adieu.
是那个女孩
lt's the girl.
再见了，苏珊娜
Au revoir, Shosanna!
第二章
Chapter Two
恶棍特工
lNGLOURlOUS BASTERDS
立正！
ALDO: Ten-hut!
我是艾多雷恩中尉
My name is Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
我要召集一个特种小组
我需要八名士兵
And l'm putting together a special team,
and l need me eight soldiers.
八个犹太裔美籍士兵
Eight Jewish American soldiers.
你们大概都听说盟军要大举进攻
Now, you all might've heard rumors
about the armada happening soon.
我们会早他们一步
Well, we'll be leaving a little earlier.
我们要以平民装扮空降法国
We're going to be dropped into France
dressed as civilians.
一旦进入敌区
Once we're in enemy territory,
就组成一支野战部队
as a bushwhacking guerrilla army,
执行一项任务，只有一项任务
we're going to be doing one thing
and one thing only.
把纳粹党赶尽杀绝
Killing Nazis.
我是不知道你们啦
l don't know about you all,
不过我远从大烟山脉
but l sure as hell didn't come down
from the goddamn Smoky Mountains,
横越五千英哩的海面
在西西里冲锋陷阵
cross 5,000 miles of water,
fight my way through half of Sicily
然后从他妈的飞机上跳下来
不是为了教纳粹党什么是人性
and Jump out of a fucking airplane
to teach the Nazis lessons in humanity.
纳粹党根本没有人性
Nazi ain't got no humanity.
他们是痛恨犹太人的杀人魔
They're the foot soldiers of a Jew-hating,
mass-murdering maniac
而且必须被消灭
and they need to be destroyed.
只要找到穿着纳粹军装的混蛋
That's why any and every son of a bitch
we find wearing a Nazi uniform,
他们都要死
they're going to die.
我的祖先是山地人吉姆布理吉
Now, l'm the direct descendent
of the mountain man Jim Bridger.
所以有一些印地安人血统
That means l got a little lndian in me.
我们的战略是阿帕契猎杀行动
And our battle plan
will be that of an Apache resistance.
我们要残杀德国佬
We will be cruel to the Germans.
让他们知道我们有多么狠
And through our cruelty,
they will know who we are.
当他们发现被分尸得
And they will find the evidence
of our cruelty
支离破碎的弟兄同胞
in the disemboweled, dismembered
就会知道我们有多么残酷
and disfigured bodies of their brothers
we leave behind us.
德国佬会忍不住想像
And the German won't be able
to help themselves
我们的手段有多残忍
but imagine the cruelty their brothers
endured at our hands,
军靴有多坚硬
刀锋有多锐利
and our boot heels
and the edge of our knives.
德国佬全都会被我们吓死
And the German will be sickened by us.
提到我们就会胆颤心惊
And the German will talk about us.
被吓得屁滚尿流
And the German will fear us.
他们晚上闭上眼睛
And when the German
closes their eyes at night
内心就会受到他们恶行的折磨
and they're tortured by their subconscious
for the evil they have done,
而且一想到我们就更害怕
it will be with thoughts of us
that they are tortured with.
听起来不错吧？
Sound good?
是的，长官！
-ALL: Yes, sir!
-Yes, sir!
这就是我要听的
That's what l like to hear.
但我要先警告你们这群战士
But l got a word of warning
for all you would-be warriors.
一旦加入，你们就欠了债
When you Join my command,
you take on debit.
欠我个人一笔债
A debit you owe me, personally.
我麾下的士兵都欠我
100个纳粹党的头皮
Each and every man under my command
owes me 100 Nazi scalps.
我要这些头皮
And l want my scalps.
你们要从100个死纳粹党脑袋
剥掉100个纳粹党的头皮
And all y'all will get me 100 Nazi scalps
taken from the heads of 100 dead Nazis.
拼了命都要给我办到
Or you will die trying!
不、不、不！
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
我还要忍受这些犹太猪多久？
How much more of these Jew swine
must l endure?
他们把我的士兵当苍蝇杀光光
They butcher my men like they were flies!
你知道我的士兵吓得魂飞魄散
传出什么谣言吗？
Do you know the latest rumor
they've conJured up
in their fear-induced delirium?
其中有一个...
The one...
...用球棒活活打死我的士兵
...that beats my boys with a bat!
那个叫“犹太熊”的恶棍...
The one they call ''The Bear Jew''...
...简直就是杀人幽灵
...is a Golem!
元首，这只是八卦而已
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
My Fuhrer, this is Just soldiers' gossip.
没人相信“犹太熊”是杀人幽灵
No one really believes ''The Bear Jew''
is a Golem.
为什么？
Why not?
他们像亡灵一样逃过追捕
They seem to be able to elude capture
like an apparition.
还可以随心所欲现身和消失
They seem to be able to appear and
disappear at will.
你们想证明他们有血有肉？
You want to prove they're flesh and blood?
那就把他们抓来！
Then bring them to me!
我要剥光他们
倒吊在巴黎铁塔
l will hang them naked, by their heels,
from the Eiffel Tower!
然后再把尸体丢进下水道...
And then throw their bodies in the sewers...
...让巴黎的老鼠享用大餐！
...for the rats of Paris to feast!
克利斯！
Kliest!
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN
ON INTERCOM)
是的，元首
Yes, my Fuhrer!
下令给驻守在法国的德国士兵
l have an order l want relayed to all
German soldiers stationed in France.
那个叫“犹太熊”的恶棍
从此不准有人这么叫他
The Jew degenerate
known as ''The Bear Jew,''
henceforth, is never to be referred
to as The Bear Jew again.
是，元首
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN)
Yes, my Fuhrer!
您还想见巴兹二等兵吗？
Do you still wish to see Private Butz?
巴兹二等兵是什么东东？
Who and what is a Private Butz?
他是您要亲自接见的大兵
He's the soldier
you wanted to see personally.
他的小队被恶棍特工突袭
His squad was ambushed
by Lt. Raine's Jews.
他是唯一的生还者
He was its only survivor.
没错，我要见他，谢谢提醒
lndeed, l do want to see him.
Thank you for reminding me.
派他进来
Send him in.
突袭过后，只有我
芮曼中士和洛魏没有死
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
Sergeant Rachtmann, Ludwig and l
were the only ones left alive
after the ambush.
一个人看守我们
其他人在剥死人头皮
While one man guarded us,
the rest removed the hair.
喂，赫希堡
Hey, Hirschberg.
把德国中士押过来
Send that Kraut sarge over.
你，走吧
HlRSCHBERG: You. Go.
韦纳芮曼中士
Sergeant Werner Rachtman.
艾多雷恩中尉，幸会
Lieutenant Aldo Raine. Pleased to meet you.
你知道“坐下来”的意思吧？
You know what ''sit down'' means, Werner?
-知道
-那就坐下来
-Yes.
-Then sit down.
你的英文好不好？
How is your English, Werner?
有需要的话，几位弟兄会翻译
Because if need be, we got
a couple of fellows who can translate.
魏奇呢
Wicki here,
是个奥地利籍犹太人
趁情况尚好时逃出慕尼黑
an Austrian-Jew, got the fuck out
of Munich while the getting was good.
入了美籍，徵召入伍
回来找你们报仇
Became American, got drafted,
come back to give y'all what for.
上面那个你可能认得
Another one up there
you might be familiar with.
雨果史提格中士
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
听过他吗？
Heard of him?
每名德军都听过雨果史提格
Everybody in the German Army
has heard of Hugo Stiglitz.
雨果史提格
雨果大名鼎鼎的原因很简单
MALE NARRATOR.; The reaSon
for Hugo Stiglitz'S celebrity
among German SoldierS iS Simple.
身为德军士兵
他却杀了13名盖世太保军官
AS a German-enliSted man,
he killed 13 GeStapo officerS.
但是德军高层领导饶他一命
InStead of putting him up againSt a wall,
反而决定把他送回柏林
the High Command
decided to Send him back to Berlin
藉以杀鸡儆猴
to be made an example of.
不用说
当恶棍特工听到他的事
NeedleSS to Say,
once the BaSterdS heard about him,
他就没被送回柏林
he never got there.
雨果史提格中士？
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz?
艾多雷恩中尉
这些是恶棍特工
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
These are the Basterds.
听过吗？
Ever heard of us?
我只想说我们是你的大粉丝
We Just want to say
we're a big fan of your work.
就刺杀纳粹来说
When it comes to killing Nazis,
我觉得你很有才华
l think you show great talent.
我看人一向很准
And l pride myself for having an eye
for that kind of talent.
不过你只是业余的B咖
But your status as a Nazi killer
is still amateur.
我们想知道你想不想当A咖
We all come here to see
if you want to go pro.
我假设你听过我们的名号
Can l assume you know who we are?
你是阿帕契人艾多
You're Aldo the Apache.
你听过我们
Werner, if you heard of us,
应该知道
咱们不干抓战俘这门生意
you probably heard we ain't
in the prisoner-taking business.
只干杀光纳粹的生意
而且这门生意兴隆
We in the killing Nazi business,
and, cousin, business is a-booming.
没错
HlRSCHBERG:
(LAUGHlNG) Oh, yeah.
现在我们只有两个选择
Now, that leaves two ways
we can play this out.
毙了你或是放你走
Either kill you or let you go.
你能不能活着走出壕沟
Whether or not you're going
to leave this ditch alive
全要看你的选择
depends entirely on you.
前面不远有一座果园
Up the road a piece, there's an orchard.
除了你们
我们知道那里也有巡逻队
Besides you, we know there's another Kraut
patrol fucking around here somewhere.
要是其中有个神枪手
lf that patrol were to have any crack shots,
他就会高兴得不得了
that orchard would be
a goddamn sniper's delight.
你想再吃到德国酸菜三明治
So if you ever want to eat
a sauerkraut sandwich again,
就得在地图上指出他们的位置
you got to show me on
this here map where they are.
你得告诉我那里有多少德军
你也得告诉我
You got to tell me how many they are,
and you got to tell me
他们拥有什么样的火力
what kind of artillery
they're carrying with them.
你该不会认为我会透露军情
让同胞的生命陷入危险吧
You can't expect me to divulge information
that would put German lives in danger.
小韦，你错了
我就是这么认为
Well, now, Werner, that's where you're
wrong, because that's exactly what l expect.
我得知道有多少德军躲在树丛
l need to know about
Germans hiding in trees.
你也得告诉我
你得马上告诉我
And you need to tell me.
And you need to tell me right now.
用你那根手指
Now, Just take that finger of yours
指出德军巡逻队的位置
and point out on this here map
where this party is being held,
说出有多少人
还有他们有什么武器
how many is coming
and what they brought to play with.
我恭敬地拒绝
l respectfully refuse, sir.
听到吗？
Hear that?
听到
Yes.
那是唐尼唐诺维兹中士
That's Sergeant Donny Donowitz.
你可能对他的绰号比较熟
You might know him better by his nickname.
犹太熊
The Bear Jew.
你听过阿帕契人艾多
一定也听过犹太熊
Now, if you heard of Aldo the Apache,
you got to have heard about The Bear Jew.
-我听过犹太熊
-你听过他什么事？
-l heard of The Bear Jew.
-What did you hear?
他用棒子打死德国士兵
Beats German soldiers with a club.
他用球棒把敌人的脑袋打爆
He bashes their brains in
with a baseball bat, what he does.
小韦，我再问你最后一次
And, Werner, l'm going to ask you
one last goddamn time,
你再恭敬地拒绝
我就要把犹太熊叫来
and if you still respectfully refuse,
l'm calling The Bear Jew over.
他会拿着他那根大球棒
He's going to take that big bat of his,
打到你的脑袋开花
and he's going to
beat your ass to death with it.
给我用你舔过德国香肠的手指
Now, take your
Wiener-schnitzel-licking finger,
在地图上指出我要的情报
and point out on this map
what l want to know.
去你的
Fuck you.
也去你的犹太走狗
And your Jew dogs.
老实说，你把我们逗得很乐
Actually, Werner,
we're all tickled to hear you say that.
因为看唐尼把纳粹活活给打死
Quite frankly, watching Donny
beat Nazis to death
就像看电影一样
唐尼！
is the closest we ever get
to going to the movies. Donny!
是
DONNY: Yeah?
这里有个德国佬想为国牺牲
Got us a German here
who wants to die for country.
让他如愿以偿吧
Oblige him.
这是你杀犹太人得到的奖章？
Did you get that for killing Jews?
英勇奖章
Bravery.
哦，不
BASTERD 1 : Oh, no!
BASTERD 2: Oh, no!
唐尼！
Donny!
唐尼
BASTERD: Yeah, Donny!
换作是我，早就挫赛了
About now l'd be shitting
my pants if l was you.
全垒打王又击出一支红不让
Teddy Fucking Williams
knocks it out of the park!
全场的球迷都欢声雷动
Fenway Park is on its feet
for Teddy Fucking Ballgame!
他把球打到球场外的街上
He went yard on that one,
on to fucking Lansdowne Street!
你！
You!
该死，赫希堡
Damn it, Hirschberg!
唐尼，把另一个带来，活的！
Donny, bring that other one over here. Alive!
给我站起来，轮到下一名打者
Get the fuck up! Batter up. You're on deck!
我K你，你就会应声倒地
Two hits. l hit you, you hit the ground.
会说英文吗？
English?
魏奇
ALDO: Wicki.
问他想不想活
Ask him if he wants to live.
叫他指出德军的位置
Tell him to point out on this map
the German position.
问他人数有多少
Ask him how many Germans.
大约12个
Around about 1 2.
他们有什么火力？
What kind of artillery?
你怎么能活着回来？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
How did you survive this ordeal?
他们放我走
They let me go.
当你报告这件事
Now, when you report what happened here,
千万别说你泄密，你会被枪决
you can't tell them you told us
what you told us. They'll shoot you.
他们会想知道你有多特别
我们才会饶你一命
They're going to want to know
why you so special, we let you live.
所以告诉他们
我们要你替我们打广告
So tell them, we let you live so you could
spread the word through the ranks
遇到我们的德军会死得很惨
what's going to happen
to every Nazi we find.
你啥都不准说
一个字都不准说
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
You are not to tell anybody anything.
Not one word of detail!
只能说你们被突袭，你逃走了
Your outfit was ambushed,
and you got away!
然后就乖乖闭嘴
Not one word more!
是，元首
Yes, my Fuhrer.
你像别的生还者留下刻印吗？
Did they mark you like they did
the other survivors?
是的，元首
Yes, my Fuhrer.
你没战死，回家后要干嘛？
Now that you've survived the war,
when you get home, what you going to do?
我要抱着我娘死都不放
l will hug my mother like
l've never hugged her before.
他要抱他娘
WlCKl: He's going to hug his mother.
真孝顺
Well, ain't that nice?
问他会不会脱掉军服？
Ask if he's going to take off his uniform.
我不但会脱掉，还会烧掉
(BUTZ SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Not only shall l remove it,
but l intend to burn it.
他会把它烧掉
WlCKl: He's going to burn it.
我就知道，这可不行
Yeah, that's what we thought.
We don't like that.
咱们喜欢穿军服的纳粹
这样才能立刻认出来
See, we like our Nazis in uniforms.
That way you can spot them.
一眼就认出来
Just like that.
脱掉军服就没人知道你是纳粹
But you take off that uniform,
ain't nobody going to know you's a Nazi.
咱们会很不爽
And that don't sit well with us.
所以我要给你脱不掉的东西
So l'm going to give you
a little something you can't take off.
中尉，你的手艺愈来愈好
You know, Lieutenant,
you're getting pretty good at that.
你知道怎样才能登上小巨蛋？
You know how you
get to Carnegie Hall, don't you?
苦练
Practice.
第三章
Chapter Three
巴黎德国之夜
GERMAN NlGHT lN PARlS
1944年
6月
JUNE
“电影院”
“兰妮莱芬斯坦领衔主演”
苏珊娜德瑞芙斯
全家惨遭屠杀四年后
明天要演什么？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
What starts tomorrow?
麦克斯林德影展
A Max Linder festival.
我一向都喜欢林德甚于卓别林
l always preferred Linder to Chaplin.
只是他从来没拍过
比《孤儿流浪记》更好的作品
Except Linder never made a film
as good as ''The Kid.''
那部片的高潮追逐戏太赞了
The chase climax of ''The Kid,'' superb.
我很喜欢这家电影院
l adore your cinema very much.
谢谢
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Merci.
你的吗？
ls it yours?
我是不是老板？
Do l own it?
对
-Oui.
是的
Oui.
你这么年轻怎会拥有电影院？
How is it a girl as young as you
owns a cinema?
我婶婶留给我的
My aunt left it to me.
谢谢你举办德国之夜影展
Merci for hosting a German night.
我别无选择...
l don't have a choice...
...但是不客气
...but you're welcome.
我很喜欢莱芬斯坦的作品...
l love the Riefenstahl mountain films...
...尤其是《匹茨帕吕的白色地狱》
...especially Piz Palu.
法国女生会崇拜莱芬斯坦很棒
lt's nice to see a French girl
who's an admirer of Riefenstahl.
我不会用“崇拜”这个词...
''Admire'' would not really be
the word l would use...
...来形容我对莱芬斯坦的感觉
...to describe my feelings towards
Fraulein Riefenstahl.
但你一定很欣赏导演帕布斯特
But you do admire the director Pabst,
don't you?
所以你才会把他放在看板上...
That's why you include his name
on the marquee...
...而其实没这必要
...when you didn't have to.
法国人一向都尊敬任何导演
l'm French.
We respect directors in our country.
就算是德国导演
Even Germans.
就算是德国导演，对
Even Germans, oui.
谢谢你的帮忙，再见
Merci for your assistance, soldier.
Adieu.
你还没换完看板
You're not finished.
我明天一早再换
l'll finish in the morning.
请问你的芳名是？
May l ask your name?
你要看我的身分证？
You wish to see my papers?
艾曼纽米敏优
Emmanuelle Mimieux.
很美的名字
That's a very pretty name.
谢谢
Merci.
你看完了吗？
Are you finished with my papers?
小姐，容我自我介绍...
Mademoiselle, may l introduce myself...
...我是弗德列克佐勒
...Fredrick Zoller.
很高兴能和电影同好聊天
Well...
...it's been a pleasure chatting
with a fellow cinema lover.
祝你好梦，小姐
Sweet dreams, mademoiselle.
再见
Adieu.
你好，小姐
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Hello, mademoiselle.
我能一起坐吗？
May l Join you?
听着，弗德列克...
Look, Fredrick...
你记得我的名字？
You remember my name?
是的
Yes.
你看起来是个好人...
Look, you seem a
pleasant enough fellow...
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
但是请你别再来烦我
Regardless, l want you to stop pestering me.
很抱歉，小姐...
l apologize, mademoiselle...
...我并不想当烦人精
...l wasn't trying to be a pest.
我只是想当朋友
l was simply trying to be friendly.
我不想当你的朋友
l don't wish to be your friend.
为什么？
Why not?
别幼稚了，你明知道原因
Don't act like an infant. You know why.
我不只是德国士兵
l'm more than Just a uniform.
对我来说你就是
Not to me.
如果你这么想交法国女友...
lf you are so desperate
for a French girlfriend...
...我建议你去维琪城
...l suggest you try Vichy.
你是什么人？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Who are you?
我以为我只是个德国士兵
l thought l was Just a uniform.
你不只是德国士兵
You're not Just a German soldier.
你是高官子弟吗？
Are you somebody's son?
德国士兵通常都是某人的子弟
Most German soldiers are somebody's son.
你很幸运交到战争英雄男友
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
You're a very lucky girl,
catching a brave war hero.
...不，这位小姐不是我女友
--No, no, no, no, the
mademoiselle is not my girlfriend.
你能签“亲爱的芭碧”吗？
Can you write ''Amour Babette''?
原来你是战争英雄
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
So you're a war hero.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
我一个人死守围城的钟塔
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
l was alone in a bell tower
in a walled off city.
我在鸟巢里只有一千发子弹...
lt was myself and a thousand
rounds of ammo, in a bird's nest...
...必须对抗三百名敌军
...against three hundred enemy soldiers.
什么是鸟巢？
What's a bird's nest?
狙击手对钟塔的说法
A bird's nest is what a sniper
would call a bell tower.
钟塔很高，有360度视野
lt's a high structure, offering
a three hundred and sixty degree view.
对神枪手来说极占优势
Very advantageous for marksmen.
你杀了几个敌军？
How many did you kill?
68个
Sixty-eight.
第1天
The first day.
150个...
A hundred and fifty...
...第2天
...the second day.
32个，第3天
Thirty-two the third day.
到了第4天，敌军就撤退
On the fourth day they exited the city.
我的事迹在德国家喻户晓...
Naturally, my war story received a
lot of attention in Germany...
...所以大家都认得我
...that's why they all recognize me.
他们称我为德国的约克中士
They call me the German Sergeant York.
也许还想把你的故事拍成电影
Maybe they'll make a film
about your exploits.
约瑟夫戈培尔导演也这么想
Well, that's Just what
Joseph Goebbels thought.
于是拍了一部《祖国的荣耀》
So he did and called it ''Nation's Pride.''
他们要我演我自己...
And they wanted me to play myself...
...于是我就去演了
...so l did.
约瑟夫认为这是他的旷世巨作
Joseph thinks this movie will
be proven to be his masterpiece.
我也会是德国的范强生
And l will be the German Van Johnson.
《祖国的荣耀》讲的是你？
''Nation's Pride'' is about you?
你也是男主角？
''Nation's Pride'' is starring you?
我知道
l know.
很可笑吧？
Comical?
祝你的电影成功
也祝你和约瑟夫万事如意
Well, good luck with your movie, Private.
l hope all goes well for Joseph and yourself.
再见
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Goodbye!
-你需要帮忙吗？
-不用，我行
-Do you need help?
-No, it's okay.
需要我的话，我在仓库
lf you need me, l'll be in the
storage room.
好的，我的爱
Okay, my love.
米敏优小姐？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Mademoiselle Mimieux?
是的
Yes?
这是你的电影院？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
ls this your cinema?
对
Yes.
下来！
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Come down!
请下来
Please.
我不懂，我做了什么？
l don't understand. What have l done?
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
她想知道她做了什么
She wants to know what she's done.
给我上车
Get your ass in that car.
黑奴的后代
才让美国参加体育竞赛有竞争力
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
lt's only the offspring of slaves that allows
America to be competitive athletically.
只有黑人才能替美国
赢得奥运金牌
American Olympic gold can be
measured in Negro sweat.
约瑟夫戈培尔博士
希特勒第三帝国的第二把交椅
很好，你来了
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Good, you came.
我不确定你肯不肯接受邀请
l wasn't sure whether or not
you'd accept my invitation.
邀请？
lnvitation?
你说的就是这个女生？
(GOEBBELS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
是的，戈培尔博士
ls that the young lady in question, Fredrick?
Yes, it is, Dr. Goebbels.
艾曼纽，我希望你认识一个人
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Emmanuelle, there is somebody
l want you to meet.
艾曼纽米敏优
容我介绍宣传部长...
Emmanuelle Mimieux, l'd like to introduce
you to the minister of propaganda...
...以及德国电影工业的领导
...the leader of
the entire German film industry...
...我当了演员后也是我的老板
约瑟夫戈培尔博士
...and now that l'm an actor, my boss,
Dr. Joseph Goebbels.
我早就久仰你的大名
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Your reputation precedes you,
Fraulein Mimieux.
这位是戈培尔先生的口译官...
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
And normally, this is Herr Goebbels'
French interpreter...
...法兰茜丝孟迪娜小姐
...Mademoiselle Francesca Mondino.
你好
Hello.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
你见过少校了
And you've met the MaJor.
我还没有自我介绍
盖世太保狄特韩斯壮少校
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Actually, l didn't introduce myself.
MaJor Dieter Hellstrom of the Gestapo.
为你效劳，小姐
At your service, mademoiselle.
让我来...
Please allow me...
...请坐
...have a seat, please.
喝点香槟，非常好喝
Try the champagne, mademoiselle,
it's quite good.
我得说你让我有点生气
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l must say, Fraulein,
l should be rather annoyed with you.
我来到法国...
l arrive in France...
...想和我的男主角吃午饭
...and l wish to have lunch with my star.
却不知道...
Little do l know...
...他在巴黎大受欢迎
...he's become the toast of Paris.
他还得挤出时间来见我
And now he must find time for me.
一般人通常要排队个几小时
或是几天才能见到我
People wait in line hours, days to see me.
可是要见元首...
For the Fuhrer...
...和佐勒二等兵就轮到我排队
...and Private Zoller, l wait.
现在终于能够晋见这位大明星
So finally, l'm granted an audience
with the young Private.
他却一直谈你和你的电影院
And he spends the entire lunch speaking
of you and your cinema.
那就不如快点谈正事吧
So Fraulein Mimieux,
let's get down to business.
...戈培尔博士...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
--Herr Minister Doctor Goebbels...
我还没告诉她
l haven't informed her yet.
除非她是呆子，应该早就想到
Unless the girl's a simpleton,
l'm sure she's figured it out by now.
毕竟，她经营一家电影院
After all, she does operate a cinema.
法兰茜丝，告诉她
Francesca, tell her.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
他们想告诉你，佐勒二等兵...
What they are trying to tell you,
Emmanuelle, is Private Zoller...
...一直想说服戈培尔先生...
...has spent the last hour at lunch trying
to convince Monsieur Goebbels...
...把原先举行电影首映会的场地...
...to abandon previous plans for
Private Zoller's film premiere...
...换到你经营的电影院
...and change the venue to your cinema.
什么？
What?
我要自己告诉她
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
对不起，那是当然的
l wanted to inform her.
Shit! l apologize, Private, of course you did.
...怎么了？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
--What's the issue?
佐勒想亲自告诉这位小姐
The Private wanted to inform
the mademoiselle himself.
荒谬！
Nonsense!
我要先问问题，才轮到他说话
Until l ask my questions,
he has nothing to inform.
请正式记录
我没同意更换我的首映会场地
Let the record state, l have not agreed
to switch cinemas for my premiere.
遵命
Duly noted.
你有包厢吗？
You have opera boxes?
有
Yes.
几个？
How many?
两个
Two.
多一点会更好
More would be better.
大厅有几个座位？
(GOEBBELS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
How many seats in your auditorium?
350个
Three hundred and fifty.
比丽池大戏院少四百个座位
That's almost four hundred less
than The Ritz.
...可是，戈培尔博士...
--But Dr. Goebbels...
...那并不是件坏事
...that's not such a terrible thing.
你自己也说不想让每个
伪善的法国佬...
You said yourself you didn't want to
indulge every two-faced French bourgeois...
...占这么多位子
...taking up space, currying favor.
座位少一些，首映会就更特别
With less seats, it makes the
event more exclusive.
你不必吸引观众
观众要抢破头才进得去
You're not trying to fill the house,
they're fighting for seats.
而且管它的法国佬
Besides, to hell with the French.
这是德国之夜、德国电影
德国光荣的一刻
This is a German night, a German event,
a German celebration.
这一夜属于你、我...
This night is for you, me...
...德军、高层领导...
...for the German military,
the high command...
...以及他们的亲朋好友
...their family and friends.
唯一能够入场的...
The only people who should
be allowed in the room...
...只有受到故事感动的观众
...are people who will be moved by
the exploits on the screen.
你愈来愈会说话了
l see your public speaking has improved.
看来我创造了一个怪物
lt appears l've created a monster.
很有说服力的怪物
A strangely persuasive monster.
战争结束后，你会进入政治圈
When the war is over, politics await.
二等兵...
Well, Private...
...虽然你想做什么我都同意...
...though it is true,
l'm inclined to indulge you anything...
但我得先在她的戏院看场电影
l must watch a film in this young lady's
cinema before l can say, yes or no.
所以这位小姐
今晚你要举行一场私人试片会
So young lady, you are to close your
cinema for a private screening tonight.
你有什么德国片？
What German films do you have?
蓝达，你来了
Ah, Landa, you are here.
这是纳粹党卫军汉斯蓝达上校
(FREDRlCK SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Emmanuelle, this is Colonel Hans Landa
of the SS.
他会负责首映会的保安
He'll be running the security
for the premiere.
幸会了，小姐
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Charmed, mademoiselle.
再见了，苏珊娜
HANS: Au revoir, Shosanna!
我得替部长安排下一个行程
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
And now l must get the Reich Minister
to his next appointment.
她是个奴隶头子
Slave driver.
法国奴隶头子
French slave driver.
身为这场首映会的
保安主管，我必须...
(HANS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Actually, in my role as security chief
of this Joyous
German occasion, l'm afraid l must...
...和米敏优小姐谈谈
...have a word with Mademoiselle Mimieux.
谈什么？
(FREDRlCK SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
What sort of discussion?
你这二等兵好像在质疑
我这个上校的命令
(HANS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
That sounded suspiciously like a Private
questioning the order of a Colonel.
还是我想太多了？
Or am l Just being sensitive?
并不是这样，上校
(FREDRlCK SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Nothing could be further
from the truth, Colonel.
我绝不怀疑您的权力
Your authority is beyond question.
但是有关您的传闻
But your reputation does precede you.
我和米敏优小姐应该担心吗？
Should Mademoiselle Mimieux
or myself be concerned?
汉斯，这小子并无恶意...
(GOEBBELS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Hans, the boy means no harm...
...他只是出于爱意
...he's simply smitten.
不过你的确是恶名昭彰
And he's correct. Your reputation
does precede you.
放心，身为保安主管
我只是想...
(HANS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
No need for concern, you two. As security
chief, l simply need to have a chat...
...和新场地的老板谈谈
...with the possible new venue's
property owner.
你尝过这里的苹果酥皮卷吗？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Have you tried the strudel here?
没有
No, no.
其实不错吃
lt's not so terrible.
你和那位二等兵怎么会认识？
So how is it the young Private and
yourself came to be acquainted?
两份苹果酥皮卷
一份给我，一份给小姐
Yes, two strudels. One for myself and
one for the mademoiselle.
我要一杯义式浓缩咖啡
这位小姐...
For me a cup of espresso
and for the mademoiselle...
...来杯牛奶
...a glass of milk.
小姐，你正要解释...
So, mademoiselle, you were
beginning to explain...?
几天前，我没听过佐勒二等兵...
Up until a couple of days ago, l had no
knowledge of Private Zoller...
...或是他的丰功伟业
...or his exploits.
对我来说...
To me...
...他只是一位观众
我们聊过几次，但是...
...the Private was simply Just a patron
of my cinema. We spoke a few times but--
...小姐，容我打个岔
--Mademoiselle, let me interrupt you.
这只是例行公事
This is a simple formality.
你没理由这么紧张
No reason for you to feel anxious.
抱歉，我忘了点鲜奶油
l apologize, l forgot to order the cream.
...请稍等
--One moment.
等鲜奶油来了再吃
Wait for the cream.
艾曼纽，我能这么叫你吗？
So, Emmanuelle.
May l call you Emmanuelle?
可以
Oui.
艾曼纽...
So, Emmanuelle...
...解释给我听...
...explain to me...
...你这么年轻
怎么会拥有一家电影院？
...how does it happen, that a young lady
such as yourself, comes to own a cinema?
你先请
After you.
怎样？
Verdict?
我说过，不错吃吧
Like l said, not so terrible.
你正在解释拥有电影院的事
You were explaining the origin
of your cinema ownership.
它本来是我叔叔和婶婶的
The cinema originally belonged
to my aunt and uncle.
他们叫什么？
What are their names?
尚皮耶和艾黛米敏优
Jean-Pierre and Ada Mimieux.
现在他们人呢？
Where are they now?
我叔叔死于闪电战
My uncle was killed during Blitzkrieg.
真可怜
Pity.
请继续说
Continue.
艾黛婶婶去年春天死于热病
Aunt Ada passed away
from fever last spring.
真遗憾
Regrettable.
你有一名黑人员工，对吧？
lt's come to my attention you have a
Negro in your employ. ls that true?
对
Oui.
他是法国人
He is a Frenchman.
他叫马瑟
His name is Marcel.
他从电影院开张后就做到现在
He worked with my aunt and uncle
since they opened the cinema.
除了他就没别的员工
He's the only other one who works with me.
他是做什么的？
Doing what?
他是放映师
ProJectionist.
技术好吗？
ls he any good?
最优秀的
The best.
看得出这工作对那种人最适合
Actually, one could see where that
might be a good trade for them.
你也会操作放映机吗？
Can you operate the proJectors?
当然会
Of course l can.
以我对戈培尔部长的了解...
Knowing the Reich Minister as l do...
我很确定...
l'm quite positive...
...他绝对不会把首映会的成败...
...he wouldn't want the success
or failure of his illustrious evening...
...交到一个黑人手中
...dependent on the prowess of a Negro.
所以...
So...
...如果我们真的...
...if it comes to pass...
...要在你的戏院举行首映会...
...we hold this event at your venue...
...虽然你的黑人员工技术优良...
...talented no doubt,
as your Negro may be...
...但是你必须...
...you will...
...亲自操作放映机
...operate the proJectors.
你能接受吗？
ls that acceptable?
可以
Oui.
来根香烟？
Cigarette?
这不是法国烟
They are not French.
这是德国烟
They are German.
我另外有件事想问你
l did have something else
l wanted to ask you.
不过我一下子突然想不起来
But right now, for the life of me,
l can't remember what it is.
无所谓，一定不重要
Oh, well, must not have been important.
今晚见
'Til tonight.
我挺喜欢这间朴实的电影院
(GOEBBELS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l must say, l appreciate the modesty
of this cinema.
非常庄重，几乎像是教堂
Your cinema has real respect, almost
church like.
别说我们不能弄得更豪华
Not to say we couldn't spruce the
place up a bit.
也许我会去罗浮宫
挑几尊希腊雕像摆在大厅
Maybe l'll go to the Louvre,
pick up a few Greek nudes,
and scatter them about the lobby.
你喜欢《幸运小子》吗？
So, Emmanuelle, how did
you like ''Lucky Kids''?
我很喜欢莉莲哈维
(SHOSANNA SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
l quite like Lilian Harvey.
那叛逃的贱人！
(GOEBBELS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Lilian Harvey!
别在我面前提到这名字！
Never mention that name again
in my presence!
我们该怎么做？
Hey...
...what the fuck are we supposed to do?
我们要替纳粹举办首映会
lt looks like we're supposed
to have a Nazi premiere.
我问你，我们该怎么做？
Like l said,
what the fuck are we supposed to do?
我得跟你好好谈谈
Well, l need to talk with you about that.
我不懂，你在说什么？
l'm confused, what are we talking about?
让电影院挤满纳粹然后烧掉它
Filling the cinema with Nazis
and burning it down to the ground.
说这件事的不是我
l'm not talking about that.
而是你
You are talking about that.
现在说这件事的是我们
No, we're talking about that, right now.
我们能避免电影院被烧掉...
lf we can keep this place from burning
down by ourselves...
...也能故意把电影院烧掉
...we can burn it down by ourselves?
没错，我们办得到
Oui, Shosanna, we could do that.
我们有350部硝酸盐胶卷影片...
And with Madame Mimieux's
350 nitrate film print collection...
...根本不需要炸药
...we wouldn't even need explosives...
...对吧？
...would we?
你是说不需要更多炸药吧
(SCOFFS)
You mean we wouldn't need
any more explosives?
当时
35厘米硝酸盐胶卷非常易燃
MALE NARRATOR.; At that time,
35 millimeter nitrate film waS So flammable
就连一卷胶卷也不准带上电车
that you couldn't even
bring a reel onto a Streetcar.
你不能把胶卷带上车
Hey, you can't bring those here
on a public vehicle.
-那些是电影胶卷，对吧？
-对
-They're films, ain't they?
-Yes.
那是易燃物，给我下车
Then they're flammable. Go on, hop off.
硝酸盐胶卷比纸张易燃三倍
MALE NARRATOR.; BecauSe nitrate film
burnS three timeS faSter than paper.
苏珊娜收藏了
ShoSanna haS a collection
350多部硝酸盐胶卷影片
of over 350 nitrate film printS.
我要在首映会当晚把戏院烧掉
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
l am going to burn down the cinema
on Nazi night.
就算我也会被烧死...
And if l'm going to burn down the cinema...
...那是一定会的...
...which l am...
...我们都知道你不会让我单独做
...we both know, you're not
going to let me do it by myself.
因为你爱我，我也爱你
你是我在世上唯一能信任的人
Because you love me. And l love you.
And you're the only person on this earth
l can trust.
但我们要做的不仅如此
But that's not all we're going to do.
阁楼的摄影器材还能用吗？
Does the filmmaking equipment in the attic
still work?
我知道摄影机能用
收音器材呢？
l know the film camera does.
How about the sound recorder?
还能用
Quite well, actually.
我上周用来录一位吉他手
效果超赞
l recorded a new guitarist l met
in a cafe last week. lt works superb.
为什么需要摄影器材？
Why do we need filmmaking equipment?
因为亲爱的马瑟...
Because Marcel, my sweet...
...我们要拍一部影片
...we're going to make a film.
只放给纳粹看
Just for the Nazis.
第四章
Chapter Four
电影院行动
OPERATlON KlNO
这里请，中尉
MAN: Right this way, Lieutenant.
艾奇希考斯中尉报到
Lieutenant Archie Hicox reporting, sir.
我是艾德芬纳奇将军，稍息
General Ed Fenech. At ease, Hicox.
来杯酒？
Drink?
如果是威士忌加水就来一杯
lf you offer me a scotch and plain water,
l could drink a scotch and plain water.
好样的，自己去调一杯
That-a-boy, Lieutenant.
Make it yourself like a good chap, will you?
酒吧在地球仪里面
The bar is in the globe.
您要来点什么吗？
Something for yourself, sir?
威士忌，什么都不加
Whiskey. Straight. No Junk in it.
根据档案，你的德语流利
lt says here that you speak German fluently.
我说得可溜的呢
Like a KatzenJammer Kid.
-你在战前的职业？
-我是个影评人
-And your occupation before the war?
-l'm a film critic.
-说说你有哪些作品
-这么说吧
-List your accomplishments.
-Well, sir, such as they are,
我替《电影与电影人》杂志
写过文章和影评
l write reviews and articles for
a publication called FilmS and FilmmakerS,
我也出版过两本书
and l've had two books published.
不错
别谦虚，书名是什么？
lmpressive. Don't be modest, Lieutenant.
What are their titles?
第一本是
The first book was called
《眼、心、灵的艺术》
20年代德国电影研究
Art of the EyeS, the Heart and the Mind.;
A Study of German Cinema in the '20S.
第二本是《24格达文西》
And the second one was called
Twenty-Four Frame da Vinci.
针对德国导演帕布斯特作品
潜文本的影评研究
lt's a sub textual film criticism study
of the work of German director G.W. Pabst.
-我们要敬什么？
-敬...
-What should we drink to, sir?
-Well...
-希特勒沉沦
-沉沦到地狱
-Down with Hitler.
-All the way down, sir.
没错
Yes.
你熟悉第三帝国的德国片吗？
Are you familiar with German cinema
under the Third Reich?
熟，我没看过这三年来的作品
Yes. Obviously, l haven't seen any
of the films made in the last three years,
-不过我很熟悉
-解释给我听
-but l'm familiar with it.
-Explain it to me.
什么？
Pardon, sir?
这项小任务需要
第三帝国德国电影工业的知识
Well, this little escapade of ours requires
a knowledge of the German film industry
解释给我听
戈培尔掌管的UFA电影公司
under the Third Reich.
Explain to me UFA under Goebbels.
戈培尔认为他制作的电影
Goebbels considers the films he's making
将是德国电影的新纪元
to be the beginning of a new era
in German cinema.
而不是他认为20年代
An alternative to what he considers
犹太裔德国知识分子的电影
the Jewish-German intellectual cinema
of the '20s,
以及被犹太人掌控的好莱坞
and the Jewish-controlled dogma
of Hollywood.
他做得怎样？
How's he doing?
抱歉，请再问一遍
Frightfully sorry, sir. Once again?
你说他想取代犹太人的电影
You say he wants to take on the Jews
at their own game.
尤其想和路易斯梅耶较劲
Well, compared to, say, Louis B. Mayer,
-他做得怎样？
-非常好
-how's he doing?
-Quite well, actually.
戈培尔掌管之后的8年来
德国电影的观众持续增加
Since Goebbels has taken over,
film attendance has steadily risen
in Germany over the last eight years.
但戈培尔不把梅耶当成对手
But Louis B. Mayer wouldn't be
Goebbels' proper opposite number.
他自认比较像大卫塞兹尼克
l believe Goebbels sees himself
closer to David O. Selznick.
跟他说吧
Brief him.
希考斯中尉
我现在要说明电影院行动
Lieutenant Hicox, at this point and time
l'd like to brief you on Operation Kino.
三天后
Three days from now
约瑟夫戈培尔
将在巴黎举办一场电影首映会
Joseph Goebbels is throwing a gala
premiere of one of his new movies in Paris.
-哪一部电影？
-《祖国的荣耀》
-What film, sir?
-The motion picture is called Nation'S Pride.
这场欢乐的德国电影首映会
ln attendance
at this Joyous Germatic occasion
会有戈培尔、戈林、鲍曼
以及高层领导人都会出席
will be Goebbels, Goring, Bormann,
and most of the German High Command
包括党卫军
以及盖世太保的高阶军官
including all high ranking officers
of both the SS and the Gestapo,
还有纳粹电影宣传部的明星
as well as luminaries
of the Nazi propaganda film industry.
纳粹菁英齐聚一堂？
The master race at play?
基本上，混蛋都聚在一起
Basically, we have all our rotten eggs
in one basket.
电影院行动的目的
The obJective of Operation Kino,
就是炸死他们
blow up the basket.
他们会像去年的残雪
从地球上蒸发消失
And like the snows of yesteryear,
gone from this earth.
太好了
Jolly good, sir.
一组美国特工部队渗入敌区
An American Secret Service outfit
that lives deep behind enemy lines
他们会协助你们
will be your assist.
德国人称他们为
“恶棍特工”
The Germans call them the Basterds.
恶棍特工，没听过
The Basterds. Never heard of them.
那是最高机密，你当然没听过
Whole point of the Secret Service, old boy,
you not hearing of them.
不过德国士兵都听过他们
这群美国佬被视为恶魔
But the Jerries have heard of them, because
these Yanks have been them the devil.
你要空降到法国
距离巴黎24公里
You'll be dropped into France,
about 24 kilometers outside of Paris.
恶棍特工会等着你
The Basterds will be waiting for you.
你要先到一个叫内汀的小村庄
First thing, you'll go to a little village
called Nadine.
内汀
ln Nadine,
那里有一家路易斯安酒馆
there's a tavern called La Louisiane.
你要跟我们的双面间谍碰面
她会替你搞定一切
There you'll rendezvous with
our double agent. She'll take it from there.
她会带你潜入首映会
She's the one who is going to get you
into the premiere.
到时候会有你、她
和两名德国出生的恶棍特工
lt'll be you, her, and two German-born
members of the Basterds.
她也会安排你需要的一切
She's also made all the other arrangements
you're going to need.
我该怎么认出她？
How will l know her?
这对你不会是个问题
l suspect
that won't be too much trouble for you.
-她是布莉姬范海慕丝玛克
-布莉姬范海慕丝玛克？
-Your contact is Bridget von Hammersmark.
-Bridget von Hammersmark?
德国电影明星是英国的间谍？
(CHUCKLlNG) The German movie star
is working for England?
对，这两年来都是
Yes, for the last two years now.
电影院行动是她的心血结晶
One could even say that Operation Kino
was her brainchild.
-原来如此
-t了吗？
-lndeed.
-Got the gist?
t了，巴黎愈夜愈美丽
l think so, sir. Paris when it sizzles.
内汀村
The village of
Nadine
你没说会合点是地下室
You didn't say the goddamn rendezvous
is in a fucking basement.
-我也不知道
-你说是在酒馆
-l didn't know.
-You said it was in a tavern.
-这是酒馆呀
-酒馆的地下室
-lt is a tavern.
-Yeah, in a basement.
在地下室战斗困难重重
You know, fighting in a basement
offers a lot of difficulties.
第一，你要在地下室战斗
Number one being,
you're fighting in a basement.
要是发现她根本不在呢？
What if we go in there
and she's not even there?
我们就要等
We wait.
放心，她是英国间谍
一定会出现的
Don't worry. She's a British spy.
She'll make the rendezvous.
-史提格，对吧？
-没错
-Stiglitz, right?
-That's right, sir.
听说你很会用刀
l hear you're pretty good with that.
我们不是来找麻烦的
You know, we're not looking
for trouble right now.
只是和联络人碰面
应该不会有事
Simply making contact with our agent.
Should be uneventful.
不过要是我错了
事情出了差错
However, the off chance l'm wrong,
things prove eventful,
我希望大家都能保持冷静
l need to know we can all remain calm.
我看起来不冷静吗？
l don't look calm to you?
既然你都这么说
我猜你很冷静
Well, now that you put it like that,
l guess you do.
你的德裔手下史提格
他不太爱说话，对吧？
This Jerry of yours, Stiglitz,
not exactly the loquacious type, is he?
你需要的是爱说话的人吗？
ls that the kind of man you need?
Loquacious type?
说的好，中尉
Fair point, Lieutenant.
要是出状况，该怎么做？
So you all get in trouble in there,
what are we supposed to do?
打赌能不能全身而退？
Make bets on how it all comes out?
如果出状况，我们都能处理
lf we get into trouble, we can handle it.
要是真的出状况，你得确保
But if trouble does happen,
we need you to make damn sure
不管是德国佬或法国佬
全都不能逃出去
no Germans, or French, for that matter,
escape from that basement.
要是范海慕丝玛克的身分曝光
整项行动就会泡汤
lf Frau von Hammersmark's cover
is compromised, the mission is kaput.
提到范海慕丝玛克小姐
是谁挑在这死亡陷阱碰面？
Speaking of Frau von Hammersmark, whose
idea was it for the death-trap rendezvous?
-是她挑的
-那敢情好
-She chose the spot.
-lsn't that Just dandy?
她不是战略专家，只是个演员
Look, she's not a military strategist.
She's Just an actress.
白痴都知道不能在地下室战斗
You don't got to be Stonewall Jackson to
know you don't want to fight in a basement.
她不是挑战斗的地点
She wasn't picking a place to fight.
而是没有德国佬的秘密地点
She was picking a place isolated
and without Germans.
...我是男的...
--So, l'm male...
...而且是虚构的文学角色...
...l'm a fictional,
literary character from the past...
...我是美国佬，很有争议性
...l'm American, and that's controversial.
一点争议性都没有
No, it's not controversial at all.
作者的国籍和角色的国籍无关
The nationality of the author has nothing
to do with the nationality of the character.
角色只是角色
The character is the character.
哈姆雷特是丹麦人不是英国人
Hamlet is not British. He is Danish.
没错，这角色出生在美国
So yes, this character was born in America.
这样嘛
Well then.
玛蒂达
Mathilda.
松子酒？
Schnapps? Schnapps?
松子酒...松子酒...
Schnapps...Schnapps...Schnapps.
五杯松子酒
(ORDERlNG lN GERMAN AND FRENCH)
Five schnapps, please.
要是我有老婆...
lf l had a wife...
...我该叫她贱内吗？
...would she be called a squaw?
Yes!
对！
He's got it.
他懂了
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
还有三个问题
Three more questions!
我的亲兄弟是“老碎手”吗？
ls my blood brother Old Shatterhand?
对！
Yes!
作者是卡尔梅吗？
Did Karl May write me?
对！
Yes!
所以你是谁？
So who are you?!
我是“威尼图”，阿帕契酋长
l am ''Winnetou,'' chief of the Apaches!
对！
Yes!
很厉害！超厉害的！
That was good! That was good!
That was good!
喝酒吧！
Now down with the glasses!
干了啦
Cheers.
干了
注意！
(FEMALE SERGEANT SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Attention!
大伙儿们好
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Hello, my lovelies.
坐吧
Take a seat.
我马上过来
我得向五位新朋友说掰掰
l will Join you in moments. l'm Just saying
goodbye to my five new friends here.
慢慢来，范海慕丝玛克夫人
No hurry, Frau von Hammersmark.
Take your time.
尽管玩，我们在这里等你
EnJoy yourself.
We'll be Just over here waiting.
艾瑞克，那些是我在等的朋友
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH AND GERMAN)
Eric, my love.
Those are the friends l've been waiting for.
他们喝什么都我请客
Please treat them to anything they like.
范海慕丝玛克夫人，悉听尊便
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Frau von Hammersmark.
Your wish is my command.
军官们...
Officers...
...看来小姐要请客
...it would appear
the drinks are on the fraulein.
-各位要喝什么？
-威士忌
-What would you like?
-Whiskey.
两杯威士忌
Two whiskeys.
-三杯威士忌
-三杯威士忌，没问题
-Three whiskeys.
-Three whiskeys, very well.
祝你们今晚玩得愉快
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l wish you a wonderful evening.
-你也是
-谢谢大家
-Same to you.
-l thank you.
你的卡片！
Your card!
对，没错
Yes, you're right.
让我看
Let's see.
成吉思汗！我绝对猜不到
Genghis Khan!
l would never have gotten that.
你当然猜得到
But of course you would have!
亲爱的
Hello, darling.
你好吗？
How are you?
很高兴见到你
So good to see you.
我以为这地方都是法国人
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN SOFTLY)
l thought this place was supposed to
have more French than Germans?
通常是这样
Yes, normally that's true.
那位上士的老婆刚生小孩
The Sergeant over there's wife
Just had a baby.
他的上司让他们放假庆祝
And his commanding officer gave him
and his mates the night off to celebrate.
我们应该离开
We should leave.
不
No.
我们应该留下来
We should stay.
至少先喝杯酒
For one drink at least.
我一直在吧台等你们
l've been waiting for you in a bar.
不喝酒就离开很可疑
(CORK POPPlNG)
lt would look strange if we left
before we had a drink.
没错，保持冷静，喝你的酒
She's right.
Just be calm and enJoy your whiskey.
艾瑞克，多谢了
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
玛蒂达...
Mathilda...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
...代替范海慕丝玛克玩游戏
...come Join us in the game.
Take Frau Hammersmark's place.
她一定会爱死这游戏
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
She would love to play the game.
我会翻译...和保护她
l will translate...and protect.
别怕，小姑娘
Don't worry, pretty little thing.
要是这几只色狼吃你豆腐
我就踢爆他们屁眼
lf any of these wolves gets
out of line, l'll kick their ass in.
看好了
Watch.
扭断他的鼻子
Rip off his nose.
住手！
Stop it!
松子酒，同志们，拿起松子酒
Schnapps, schnapps, take your
schnapps in hand, comrades.
我们在玩游戏之前...
Before we go on playing...
...先喝酒
...we will drink.
敬咱们的朋友威汉
We drink to our friend Wilhelm.
还有他的小儿子...
And his little boy...
...麦斯米兰
...Maximilian.
敬麦斯！
(ALL TOASTlNG lN GERMAN)
-To Max!
有新的发展
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
There's some new development.
他们换了电影院
The cinema venue has changed.
为什么？
Why?
没人知道，不过应该没问题
No one knows but that should
not be a real problem.
换到比丽池戏院小很多的场地
The cinema it's been changed to
is considerably smaller than The Ritz.
你们带的炸弹效果会强两倍
So whatever explosives you brought for
The Ritz should be doubly effective here.
另外一个新发展...
Now the next piece of information...
...是个大消息
...is colossal.
千万别反应过度
Try not to overreact.
元首...
The Fuhrer-
...我在想喔...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
...l was Just thinking...
...你能替我儿子签名庆生吗？
...could you sign an autograph
to my son on his birthday?
当然了，我很乐意，威汉
Of course. l'd love to, Wilhelm.
英俊潇潇的上士今天当爸爸了
This handsome Staff Sergeant
Just became a father today.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
你替他取了名字吗？
Do you know the name of this progeny yet?
当然，他叫麦斯米兰
l most certainly do,
fraulein. His name is Maximilian.
麦斯米兰，很棒的名字
Maximilian, wonderful name.
谢谢你，中尉
Thank you, Lieutenant.
祝小麦斯米兰平平安安
Nothing but the best for little Maximilian.
麦斯还不知道你是谁，不过...
Max may not know who you are now but...
...我会带他看你的每部电影
...he will. l will show him all of your movies.
太好了
Good.
他会看你的电影长大...
He will grow up with your films and...
...然后把这条餐巾帖在墙上
...this napkin on his wall.
我提议大家向德国
最伟大的女演员敬酒
l propose a toast
to the greatest actress in Germany!
没有黛德丽！没有莱芬斯坦！
只有范海慕丝玛克！
There is no Dietrich! There is no Riefenstahl!
Only Von Hammersmark!
-干杯！
-Cheers!
干杯！
我再说一次...
Once again-
什么风把你吹来法国？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Frau Hammersmark,
what brings you to France?
不关你的事
None of your business!
上士
Staff Sergeant.
你醉醺醺的丑态
或许没惹毛她...
You might not have worn out
your welcome with
the fraulein with your
drunken boorish behavior...
...不过却惹毛了我
...but you have worn out
your welcome with me.
让我提醒你，你只是个士兵
Might l remind you, Staff Sergeant,
you are an enlisted man.
这桌的人都是军官
This is an officer's table!
我建议你别再骚扰范小姐...
l suggest you stop pestering the fraulein...
...回去你那一桌
...and reJoin your table.
对不起，上尉，你的口音很怪
Excuse me, Captain,
but your accent is very unusual.
你打哪儿来的？
Where are you from?
你不是醉昏了就是疯了...
You must be either completely
drunk or mad to dare...
...胆敢对上属如此无礼！
...to speak to a superior officer with
such impertinentness!
上士
Staff Sergeant.
我要你们对他的行为负责
l'm making you and you responsible for him.
我建议你们把他带走...
l suggest you take hold of your friend...
...不然就得在儿子出生当天坐牢
...or he'll spend Max's first birthday
in Jail for public drunkenness.
...我有个问题
--Might l inquire?
我跟这位新爸爸一样...
Like our young
newly christened father here...
...耳朵对口音很灵敏
...l, too, have an acute ear for accents.
我也跟他一样...
And like him...
...觉得你的口音很怪
...l, too, find yours odd.
你到底来自哪里？
From where do you hail, Captain?
少校，这太过分...
MaJor, this is highly-
...我不是问你，慕尼黑来的中尉
---l wasn't speaking to you,
Lieutenant Munich.
或是你，法兰克福来的中尉
Or you either, Lieutenant Frankfurt.
我在问听不出来自哪里的上尉
l was speaking to
Captain l-don't-know-what.
我来自帕鲁峰山脚的小村庄
l was born in a village that rests
in the shadow of the Piz Palu.
-山脚？
-对
-The mountain?
-Yes.
我们讲话都是这样
ln that village, we all speak like this.
你看过莱芬斯坦的电影吗？
Have you seen the Riefenstahl film?
-看过
-那你就该看过我
-Yes.
-Then you saw me.
记得雪撬火炬那场戏吗？
You remember the skiing torch scene?
记得
Yes.
那场戏有我、我爸、我妹
和我两个弟弟
ln that scene was myself, my father,
my sister and my two brothers.
我弟弟超帅...
My brother is so handsome...
...导演帕布斯特一直拍他的特写
...the director Pabst, gave him a Close-Up.
少校，如果你信得过我...
Herr MaJor, if my word means anything...
...我敢替这位上尉的话担保
...l can vouch for everything
the young captain has Just said.
他的确来自帕鲁峰山脚
He does hail from the bottom
of the Piz Palu.
他也真的拍过戏
而且他弟弟比他帅多了
He was in the film and his brother
is far more handsome than he.
你应该回去找朋友
You should reJoin your friends.
我能加入你们吗？
May l Join you?
请便
By all means.
太好了
Wunderbar!
原来你的怪口音是这么来的
So that's the source of your bizarre accent.
真没想到
That's extraordinary.
你来这里干嘛？
What are you doing here?
除了和美丽的小姐喝酒以外？
Aside from having a drink
with the lovely fraulein?
这我就不必替你解释
Well, that pleasure requires no explanation.
我是说来这国家
l mean in country.
你若驻守法国，我肯定认识你
You're obviously not stationed in
France or l'd know who you are.
你认识法国的每个德国人？
You know every German in France?
当然了
Worth knowing.
这就是问题所在
Well, there lies the problem.
我们不敢说自己认识每个人
We never claimed to be worth knowing.
你到底来法国干嘛？
All levity aside,
what are you doing in France?
陪范小姐参加戈培尔首映会
Attending Minister Goebbels' film
premiere as the fraulein's escort.
你是范小姐的男伴？
You are the Fraulein Hammersmark's
escort.
总得有人替她拿打火机吧
Someone has to carry her lighter.
上尉是我的男伴
其他的人是我的贵宝
The captain is my date,
but all three are my guests.
我们是老朋友...
We are old friends...
...交情很久
...who go back a long time.
比我这女明星想承认的久很多
Actually, longer than an actress
would care to admit.
既然如此...
Well, in that case...
...让我向三位幸运儿举杯敬酒
...let me raise my glass to the
three luckiest men in the room.
我也喝了
l'll drink to that.
克莉斯汀女皇
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Queen Christina.
玛塔哈莉
Mata Hari.
我得说...
l must say...
...他们在玩的游戏好像很好玩
...that game they're playing
looks like a good bit of fun.
你说的对，我没跟着玩
l didn't Join them
because you're quite right, Captain.
因为军官不该和士兵称兄道弟
An officer should not fraternize
with enlisted men.
不过呢...
But...
...既然我们都是军官
...seeing as we are all officers...
...加上是大明星的好朋友
...and sophisticated lady friends of officers.
咱们一起玩这游戏，如何？
What say we play the game?
好啊，玩一场吧
Yes, great, one game.
太好了
Wunderbar.
大兵们...
Soldiers...
...把卡片给我
...the cards.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
各位...
So gentlemen...
...游戏规则是...
...the obJect of the game is to...
...在卡片上写出名人
...write the name of a famous
person on your card.
真人或虚构角色都行
Real or fictitious, doesn't matter.
比如说可以写孔夫子或是傅满洲
For instance, you could write,
Confucius or Doctor Fu Manchu.
艾瑞克！笔拿来！
Eric! More pens.
一定要是名人，不能写你阿姨
And they must be famous, not aunt Frida.
写完了就把卡片盖在桌上
When you finish writing,
put the card face down on the table.
然后就给你右手边的人
And move it to the person on your right-
...谢了
--Thanks.
你左手边的人会把卡片给你
-the person to your left
moves his card to you.
你拿起卡片时不能看...
You pick up the card without looking at it...
...然后舔一下背面...
...lick the back...
...帖在你的额头
...and stick it on your forehead.
写吧！
Write!
快写吧
Write.
“金刚”
(VON HAMMERSMARK LAUGHlNG)
“马可波罗”
“G.W.帕布斯特”
“布莉姬荷妮”
我先示范给你们看
l'll start, give you the idea.
我是德国人吗？
Am l German?
不是
-No.
我是美国人吗？
Am l American?
不是
-No.
等等，他有去过...
Wait a minute, he goes to ---
不过他不是在美国出生
Obviously, he wasn't born in America.
所以...我去过美国罗？
So...l visited America, aye?
对
Yes.
我去美国是好事吗？
Was this visit fortuitous?
对你来说不是
Not for you.
我的故乡是不是有异国情调？
My native land,
is it what one would call, exotic?
是
(VON HAMMERSMARK AND HlCOX
SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
-Yes.
那么说，不是丛林就是东方？
That could be either a reference
to the Jungle or the Orient.
我要凭第一直觉问你们
我来自丛林吗？
l'm going to let my first instinct take over
and ask. Am l from the Jungle?
对
-Yes.
这时就能问是真人或虚构角色
Now gentlemen, around this time you could
ask whether you're real or fictitious.
我觉得答案太简单所以不问
l, however, think that's too easy,
so l won't ask that yet.
好吧...
Okay...
...我的故乡是丛林...
...my native land is the Jungle...
...我去过美国...
...l visited America...
...不过对我来说不是好事...
...but my visit was not fortuitous to me...
...这代表对别人是好事
...but the implication is
that it was to somebody else.
我从...
When l went...
...丛林到美国...
...from the Jungle to America...
...是不是坐船？
...did l go by boat?
是
-Yes.
我不是自愿的，对吗？
Did l go against my will?
对
-Yes.
我在船上被铁链铐住？
On this boat ride, was l in chains?
对
Yes.
我到了美国也被铐住展示？
When l arrived in America,
was l displayed in chains?
对
-Yes.
我是故事里去美国的黑人？
Am l the story of the Negro in America?
不对
(HlCOX SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
-No.
那我一定是金刚
Well then l must be King Kong.
答对了！
Bravo!
佩服佩服
lmpressive.
我答对了你们就得罚酒
Now, since l answered correctly, you
all need to finish your drinks.
干杯
Cheers.
现在轮到谁？
Now, who is next?
少校...
Well, MaJor...
...我无意冒犯
不过我们四个是超级好朋友
...l don't mean to be rude. But
the four of us are very good friends.
很久没有见面了
And we haven't seen each other
in quite a while.
所以，少校...
So, MaJor...
...我觉得...
...l am afraid...
...你打扰到我们
...you are intruding.
我不同意
l beg to differ, Captain.
如果范小姐觉得我打扰你们...
lt's only if the fraulein considers
my presence an intrusion...
...那我才算很白目
...that l become an intruder.
怎么样？我很白目吗？
How about it, Fraulein von Hammersmark?
Am l intruding?
没有
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
我猜也是
l didn't think so.
只有上尉不喜欢我而已
lt's simply the captain
is immune to my charms.
开玩笑的啦
l am Just Joking.
我在开玩笑，我当然很白目
Just Joking. Of course l'm intruding.
让我再替各位倒酒
然后就向范小姐和各位道别
Allow me to refill your glasses, gentlemen,
and l will bid you and the fraulein adieu.
艾瑞克有瓶33年的陈年威士忌
Eric has a bottle of
thirty-three-year-old whiskey.
来自苏格兰高地
From the Scottish Highlands.
怎么样？
What do you say, gentlemen?
你真是大方
You're most gracious, MaJor.
艾瑞克！33年威士忌！
顺便换新酒杯！
Eric! The thirty-three. And new glasses!
可别让原来的劣酒
糟蹋了佳酿
You don't want to contaminate the
thirty-three with the swill you were drinking.
几个杯子？
How many glasses?
-五个
-我不喝
-Five.
-Not for me.
我喜欢威士忌，只是喝不惯
l like scotch, scotch doesn't like me.
我也是，我还是喝香槟吧
Nor l. l'll stay with bubbly.
三个酒杯
Three glasses.
范小姐
(ERlC SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Frau von Hammersmark.
谢谢
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Thank you.
第三帝国万岁！
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
A thousand year German Reich!
第三帝国万岁！
-A thousand year Reich!
我跟你勾心斗角斗累了
l must say l grow weary
of these monkeyshines.
你听到吗？
Did you hear that?
那是我的手枪
That was the sound of my Walther.
指着你的鸟蛋的声音
Pointed right at your testicles.
你干嘛拿手枪指着我的鸟蛋？
Why do you have your Walther pointed
at my testicles?
因为你泄了底了，上尉
Because you've Just
given yourself away, Captain.
你跟威士忌一样不是来自德国
You're no more German than that scotch.
-少校
-闭嘴，婊子
(BOTH SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
-Well, MaJor.
-Shut up slut.
你想说什么？
You were saying?
看来这是两人对峙
l was saying that makes two of us.
你一坐下我就拿枪指着你鸟蛋
l've had a gun pointed at your
balls since you sat down.
这是三人对峙
That makes three of us.
这么近，连我都是神枪手
And at this range, l'm a real Fredrick Zoller.
看来情况有点不太妙
Looks like we have
a bit of a sticky situation here.
少校，你要做的是...
What's going to happen, MaJor...
...乖乖站起来陪我们走出大门
...you're going to stand up
and walk out that door with us.
不...不...想都别想
--No, no, no, no, no, no.
l don't think so.
你和我...
l'm afraid you and l...
...都知道...
...we both know, Captain...
...不管别人怎么样...
...no matter what happens to anybody else
in this room...
...咱们俩哪儿都不能去
...the two of us aren't going anywhere.
真可惜
威汉上士和他朋友要被拖下水
Too bad about Sergeant Wilhelm
and his famous friends.
你们想活命，就得毙了他们
lf any of you expect to live,
you'll have to shoot them too.
看来小麦斯从小就会是孤儿
Looks like little Max will grow up an orphan.
真可怜
How sad.
如果是这样
Well, if this is it, old boy,
希望你不介意我说英文
l hope you don't mind if l go out
speaking the King's.
请说吧，上尉
By all means, Captain.
地狱有一层
专门关浪费顶极威士忌的人
There's a special rung in hell reserved
for people who waste good Scotch.
既然我可能就快要没命
Seeing as l may be rapping
on the door momentarily,
我得说
真他妈的好喝
l must say, damn good stuff, sir.
至于我们陷入的
Now, about this pickle
这个状况
we find ourselves in.
看来你只能做一件事
lt would appear there's only
one thing left for you to do.
什么事？
And what would that be?
-史提格
-向你的纳粹鸟蛋说掰掰吧
-Stiglitz.
-Say auf wiederSehen to your Nazi balls.
外面的人，你是什么人？
You outside. Who are you?
英国人？美国人？
British? American?
什么？
What?
我们是美国人
ALDO: We're American.
你呢？
What are you?
德国人呀，猪头
l'm a German, you idiot.
你的英文倒是说得不错
ALDO: Speak English
pretty good for a German.
我同意
l agree.
所以来谈谈吧
So let's talk.
好，谈吧
ALDO: Okay, talk.
我当了爸爸
l'm a father.
我的宝宝今天在法兰克福出生
My baby was born today. ln Frankfurt.
五个钟头前
Five hours ago.
他叫麦斯
我们来这里喝酒庆祝
His name is Max.
We were in here drinking, celebrating.
他们跑来开枪杀人
不是我的错
They're the ones that came in shooting
and killing. lt's not my fault!
好啦，不是你的错
ALDO: Okay! lt wasn't your fault.
你叫什么，大兵？
What's your name, soldier?
威汉
Wilhelm.
我方有没有人还活着？
Now, is there anybody alive on our side?
-没有
-我还活着！
-No.
-l'm alive!
那是谁？
ALDO: Who's that?
这女的是你们的人吗？
ls the girl on your side?
哪个女的？
ALDO: Which girl?
你说呢？范海慕丝玛克呀！
Who do you think? Von Hammersmark.
对，她是我们的人
ALDO: Yeah, she's ours.
她没事吧？
ALDO: ls she okay?
威汉！
ALDO: Wilhelm!
她中了枪
She's been shot.
不过她还活着
But she's alive.
好吧，威汉
ALDO: Okay, Wilhelm.
咱们谈个条件如何？
What do you say we make us a deal?
你叫什么？
What's your name?
艾多
Aldo.
威汉，这是我的条件
Okay, Wilhelm, here's my deal.
让我和我的手下把那女的带走
You let me and one of my men
come down there and take the girl away.
我不拿枪，你不拿枪
No guns. No guns me, no guns you.
我们把那女的带了就走
就这么简单，威汉
And we take the girl and leave.
lt's that simple, Willi.
你走你的，我们走我们的
You go your way, we go ours.
小威汉就能长大陪他老爸打球
And little Max gets to grow up
playing catch with his daddy.
怎么样？这条件谈成了吗？
So what do you say, Willi? We got us a deal?
艾多
Aldo.
我在这里，小威
ALDO: l'm here, Willi.
我很想信任你
l want to trust you.
可是...
But...
我怎么能信任你？
But how can l?
你有什么选择？
ALDO: What choice you got, son?
好吧，好吧
Okay, okay.
艾多
Aldo,
我要信任你
l'm going to trust you.
下来吧
Come down.
喂，干嘛拿出机关枪？
我以为谈好条件了
Hey, Willi, what's with the machine gun?
l thought we had us a deal?
是啊，带着那女的就走
We still have a deal.
Now, get the girl and go.
先别急
Not so fast.
只有一个条件，非得互相信任
We only got a deal, we trust each other.
火线对峙不算是信任
And a Mexican standoff ain't trust.
你得拿枪对着我才算火线对峙
You need guns on me
for it to be a Mexican standoff.
你拿枪对着我们
决定开火，我们就死定了
You got guns on us.
You decide to shoot, we're dead.
不过他们在上面有手榴弹
只要丢下来，你就死定了
Up top, they got grenades.
They drop them down here, you're dead.
这算火线对峙，这不是条件
That's a Mexican standoff,
and that was not the deal.
没有信任就没有条件
No trust, no deal.
好吧，艾多
All right, Aldo.
好吧
Fine.
把卖国贼带走，别让我看到她
Just take that fucking traitor,
and get her out of my sight.
先别急，医生
叫他去跟他的狗玩
Not so goddamn fast, doc.
Tell him to go play with his dogs.
我们替你取出子弹前
你得先回答问题
Before we yank that slug out you,
you need to answer a few questions.
什么问题？
Few questions about what?
我们怎么会死了三个人？
About l got three men dead back there.
告诉我们到底发生什么事
Why don't you try telling us
what the fuck happened?
英国佬露了馅
被盖世太保的少校看到
The British officer blew his German act
and the Gestapo maJor saw it.
在你从头开始解释之前
Before we get into who shot John,
想问你为什么叫我们
在全是纳粹的地下室碰面？
why'd you invite my men to a rendezvous
in a basement with a bunch of Nazis?
你没看见发生什么事
l can see since you didn't see
what happened inside,
一定觉得有纳粹在很奇怪
that the Nazis being there must look odd.
没错，有个词儿能形容
Yeah, we got a word
for that kind of odd in English.
那就是很可疑
lt's called suspicious.
大家都得冷静下来
Everybody needs to calm down.
千万别胡思乱想
You're letting your imagination
get the better of you.
你也见过威汉上士
You met the sergeant yourself. Willi.
记得他吧？
You remember him, don't you?
当然了
Yeah, l remember him.
他老婆今晚刚生小孩，他才...
His wife had a baby tonight.
He had Just become a...
他才当了爸爸
He had Just become a father!
他的上司放他假和朋友庆祝
His commanding officer gave him
and his mates the night off to celebrate.
那里会有德国人
不是我设的陷阱就是纯属巧合
The Germans being there was either
a trap set by me or a tragic coincidence.
不可能两者皆是
lt couldn't be both.
他们怎么会开始开枪？
How'd the shooting start?
英国佬露了馅
The Englishman gave himself away.
怎么会？
How'd he do that?
他点了三杯酒
He ordered three glasses.
我们点三杯酒
We order three glasses.
那是德国人比的三
That's the German three.
他比的三看起来就可疑
The other looks odd.
德国佬注意到了
Germans would and did notice it.
假设那里没有德国佬
Okay, let's pretend there were no Germans
一切都照计划进行
and everything went exactly
the way it was supposed to.
下一步是什么？
What was the next step?
燕尾服
Tuxedos.
首映会到处都是高阶军官
To get them into the premiere
wearing military uniforms
他们穿军服去等于自杀
with all the military there
would've been suicide.
他们要冒充德国电影圈人士
But going as members
of the German film industry,
穿着燕尾服融入人群
they wear tuxedos
and fit in with everybody else.
我请人熬夜赶做三套燕尾服
l arranged for the tailor
to fit three tuxedos tonight.
他们要怎么潜入首映会？
How'd you intend to get them
in that premiere?
把我的皮包给我
Hand me my purse.
希考斯中尉本来是我的男伴
Lieutenant Hicox was going as my escort.
另外两个扮德国摄影师和助理
The other two were going
as a German cameraman and his assistant.
你还是能帮我们潜进去？
You still get us in that premiere?
你的德语比你朋友更溜吗？
没有
You speak German
better than your friends? No.
我有没有中弹？有！
Have l been shot? Yes!
所以我有一阵子不能走红地毯
l don't see me tripping the light fantaStique
up a red carpet anytime soon.
更别说是明晚了
Least of all, by tomorrow night.
但是，有件事你不知道
However, there's something you don't know.
电影院行动有两项最新发展
There've been two recent developments
regarding Operation Kino.
第一，场地从丽池大戏院
换到小很多的电影院
One, the venue has been changed
from The Ritz to a much smaller venue.
德国人不太会临时改变计划
Enormous change at the last minute?
That's not very Germatic.
戈培尔怎么会做这种怪事？
Why the hell is Goebbels doing stuff
so damn peculiar?
可能和第二项事有关
lt probably has something to do
with the second development.
什么事？
Which is?
希特勒要参加首映会
Der Fuhrer is attending the premiere.
关于你在巴黎...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l've been rethinking my position...
...举行《祖国的荣耀》首映会
我一直在重新考虑我的立场
...in regards to your Paris premiere
of ''Nation's Pride.''
一周一周过去...
As the weeks have gone on...
...美国佬又抢上滩头...
...and the Americans are on the beach...
...我对佐勒二等兵的英勇事迹...
...l do find myself thinking more and more...
...又考虑得更多
...about this Private Zoller.
这小子对国家奉献良多
This boy has done something tremendous
for us.
于是我开始想...
And l'm beginning to think...
...我参加首映会可能意义重大
...my participation in this event
could be meaningful.
我靠！
Fuck a duck!
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
我在想有机会刺杀希特勒
l'm thinking getting a whack
at planting old Uncle Adolf
改变了整个计划
makes this horse a different color.
所以呢？
What is that supposed to mean?
你一定要把我们弄进去
lt means you getting us in that premiere.
我大概会失去这条腿
l'm probably going to end up losing this leg.
演艺生涯也没了
Bye-bye, acting career. Fun while it lasted.
我这样该怎么走红地毯？
How do you expect me
to walk the red carpet?
兽医会把子弹取出来
Doggy doc's going to dig that slug
out your gam.
替你裹一层石膏
He's going to wrap it up in a cast,
然后你就瞎编说是登山摔断腿
and you got a good
how-l-broke-my-leg-mountain-climbing story.
德国人不是都很喜欢登山吗？
That's German, ain't it?
You all like climbing mountains, don't you?
我不喜欢
我喜欢抽烟喝酒，到餐厅吃饭
l don't. l like smoking, drinking
and ordering in restaurants.
不过我明白你的意思
But l see your point.
我们会替你注射一大桶吗啡
We fill you up with morphine
till it's coming out your ears
你就一拐一拐地走红地毯
and Just limp your little ass
up that rouge carpet.
我知道这是个蠢问题
l know this is a silly question before l ask it,
不过你们美国佬除了英文
还会哪一国语言？
but can you Americans speak
any other language than English?
我们都会说一点意大利文
We both speak a little ltalian.
口音一定很重
With an atrocious accent, no doubt.
但是不一定一开始就被戳破
But that doesn't exactly kill us in the crib.
德国人听不太懂意大利话
Germans don't have a good ear for ltalian.
你们要靠它蒙过去，对吧？
So you mumble ltalian
and brazen through it. ls that the plan?
差不多就是这样
That's about it.
听起来不错
That sounds good.
不错个屁！不然我们要回家？
lt sounds like shit.
What else are we going to do? Go home?
不，这真的行得通
No, that sounds good.
你们不凸，我就能带你们进去
lf you don't blow it, with that,
l can get you in the building.
谁要做什么？
Who does what?
我的意大利话说得最溜
所以我是你的男伴
Well, l speak the most ltalian,
so l'll be your escort.
唐尼也不赖，他是摄影师
Donowitz speaks second most,
so he'll be your ltalian cameraman.
欧玛只能当摄影助理
Omar, third most. He'll be Donny's assistant.
我不会讲意大利话
l don't speak ltalian.
所以罗，你就给我乖乖闭嘴
Like l said, third best.
Just keep your fucking mouth shut.
你们都给我马上练习
ln fact,
why don't you start practicing right now?
你升官了嘛
You've moved up in the world.
看看你，升中尉了
Look at you, Lieutenant First Class.
你还有多次以下弑上的记录
这真是不容易
And with your record of insubordination.
Truly remarkable.
那个家伙叫...
And that one's name is...
...威汉魏奇
...Wilhelm Wicki.
这个奥地利出生的犹太佬...
He's an Austrian-born Jew, who
immigrated to the United States...
...知道情势不妙就移民到美国
...when things began turning sour
for the lsraelites.
他们都是德国出生的恶棍特工
They are the two German-born
members of the Basterds.
为了突袭德军穿上德军制服
They've been known to don German
uniforms, to ambush squads.
你们为什么大老远跑来？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
What brings you all the way out here?
这不像他们的作风
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
But that doesn't look like this.
事有蹊跷
This is odd.
有一个人不见了
lt would appear somebody's missing.
一位很时髦的女士
Somebody fashionable.
大家出去！
Everybody out!
“给亲爱的麦斯”
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
''To Max, with love.''
布莉姬范海慕丝玛克
Bridget von Hammersmark.
第五章
Chapter Five
巨脸复仇记
REVENGE OF THE GlANT FACE
《祖国的荣耀》首映会
Night of ''NATlON'S PRlDE'' premiere
记得...要说英文
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Remember...in English.
好
Yes.
开麦拉
Action.
要找谁帮忙冲印呢？
But how do we get it developed?
不要命的白痴才会答应
Only a suicidal idiot like us
would develop that footage.
就算有人愿意冲印...
And suppose someone would develop
the footage...
...也不会是有音轨的35厘米拷贝
...how do we get a 35mm
print with a soundtrack?
我们要找到能冲印成
有音轨的35厘米拷贝的人
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
We find somebody who can develop
and process a 35mm print with a soundtrack.
然后逼他们帮忙...
And we make them do it...
...要不然就杀了他们
...or we kill them.
把他带过来，把头压在桌上
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Bring that fucker over here!
Put his head down on that table.
你不乖乖听我们的话...
You either do what the fuck we tell you...
...我就用斧头砍断你脑袋
...or l'll bury this ax
in your collaborating skull.
我不是卖国贼
(MAN SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
l'm not a collaborator.
马瑟，他老婆小孩认识你吗？
Marcel, do his wife and children know you?
认识
Yes.
我们杀死这只德国狗以后...
Then after we kill this dog
for the Germans...
...再去杀光他全家
...we'll go and silence them.
“赫曼戈林”
詹宁斯，秀出你的戒指
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Jannings, come on, show the ring.
快呀，这就对了
Come on, come on. There you go!
弗德列克，你看
这代表最高的艺术成就
Fredrick, have a look at it. This is
the highest artistic honor that l give.
-我感到非常荣幸
-这是你应得的
-Herr Doctor, l'm also feeling very honored.
-You deserve it, my dear Jannings!
不过今晚的首映会后
将有一名全新候选人
But l believe after the premiere today,
we have a new candidate.
艾曼纽...
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Ah, Emmanuelle...
...我要介绍世上最伟大的演员...
...l'd like you to meet the
greatest actor in the world...
...艾默詹宁斯
...Emil Jannings.
小姐，很高兴认识你
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Mademoiselle, l'm pleased to meet you.
你的戏院非常美
You have a beautiful cinema.
谢谢你，赫曼
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Thank you, Hermann.
范海慕丝玛克小姐
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Fraulein von Hammersmark.
蓝达上校，好久不见
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Colonel Landa, it's been years.
你还是一样帅气
Dashing as ever, l see.
你的腿怎么了？
So what's happened to your lovely leg?
一定是为拍德国电影而挂彩
A by-product of kicking ass in
the German cinema, no doubt.
少来这一套，老狐狸
Save your flattery, you old dog.
我太了解你
才不信你的甜言蜜语
l know too many of your former conquests
to fall into that honey pot.
说真的，到底是怎么了？
Seriously, what happened?
我竟然会傻到想要试试看...
Well, l tried my hand,
foolishly l might add...
...登山的滋味
...at mountain climbing.
结果就摔断了腿
And this is the result.
登山？
Mountain climbing?
你因为登山摔断腿？
That's how you inJured your leg
-mountain climbing?
信不信由你，是真的
Believe it or not, yes it is.
原谅我，我不是故意笑你
Forgive me, fraulein. l don't mean to
laugh at your misfortune.
只是...你会去登山？
lt's Just --- mountain climbing?
我很好奇
你怎么会想去做这种蠢事？
l'm curious, fraulein,
what could have ever compelled
you to undertake
such a foolhardy endeavor?
相信我，我不会再去了
Well, l shan't be doing it again,
l can tell you that.
石膏看来像是才刚敷上去
That cast looks as fresh
as my old Uncle Gustav.
你是昨晚去登山吗？
When were you climbing this mountain,
last night?
你的眼光真锐利
Very good eye, Colonel.
我是昨天早上去的
lt happened yesterday morning.
你是登巴黎的哪座山呀？
And where in Paris is this mountain?
我只是在逗你
No, l'm Just teasing you, fraulein.
你也知道，我最爱逗人了
You know me, l tease rough.
这三位帅哥是谁呀？
So, who are your three
handsome escorts?
他们连一句德文都不会说
l'm afraid neither three speak
a word of German.
他们是我意大利的朋友
They're friends of mine from ltaly.
这位是顶尖的特技替身
安佐葛罗米
This is a wonderful ltalian
stuntman, Enzo Gorlomi.
才华洋溢的摄影师
安东尼奥马格列提
A very talented cameraman,
Antonio Margheriti.
他的助理，多明尼克戴可可
And Antonio's camera assistant
Dominick Decocco.
各位，我的老朋友
党卫军汉斯蓝达上校
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
Gentlemen, this is an old friend,
Colonel Hans Landa of the SS.
日安
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
Hello.
各位，幸会了...
Gentlemen, it's a pleasure...
...她是德国最受爱戴的女明星...
...the friends of our cherished star,
admired by all of us,
this outright Jewel of our culture...
...我一定会从头到尾
亲自保护她
...are naturally going to be under my personal
protection for the duration of their stay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
葛罗米
Gorlomi?
我说的对吗？
Am l saying it correctly?
对，呃，没错
Yes - 'er, correct.
葛罗米
Gorlomi?
请再替我说一次...
Say it for me once please...?
葛罗米
Gorlomi.
抱歉，再说一次...
l'm sorry, again...?
葛罗米
Gorlomi.
请再说一次...
Once more...?
葛罗米
(SOFTLY) Gorlomi.
你叫什么来着...？
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
What's your name again...?
安东尼奥马格列提
Antonio Margheriti.
再说一次...
Again...?
安东尼奥马格列提
Margheriti.
再说一次
让我再听一次迷人的意大利话
One more time, but let me
really hear the music in it!
安东尼奥马格列提
Margheriti.
HANS: Margheriti.
还有你呢...？
And you...?
Dominick Decocco.
多明尼克戴可可
得帮这两位朋友找到座位
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Well, my two cameraman friends
need to find their seats.
让我看看门票
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
Let me see your tickets.
像你地位这么崇高的明星
替朋友弄到门票...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l suppose you getting premiere tickets
for your friends wouldn't be
the most difficult thing...
...应该轻而易举
...for a star of your status.
0023和0024
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
0023 and 0024.
应该不难找，再见了
That shouldn't be too difficult to find,
goodbye.
“马丁鲍曼”
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTERlNG)
乖乖！大明星耶
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Ooh la la, Danielle Darrieux.
我得下去跟那些猪猡交际
l have to go down and socialize
with these Hun pigs.
我们再复习一遍
Let's go over it again.
第一卷在一号放映机
Reel one is on the first proJector.
第二卷...
Reel two...
...在二号放映机
...is on the second.
第三卷在卷轴上
The third one is on the spool.
第四卷随时能放映
And the fourth one is ready to go.
狙击手枪杀敌军的戏份...
Okay, the big sniper battle
in the film...
...从第三卷中间开始
...begins around the middle
of the third reel.
我们的影片从第四卷开始
Our film comes in on the fourth reel.
第三卷快结束时...
Somewhere towards the end
of the third reel...
...到楼下把大门锁死
...go down and lock the doors
of the auditorium.
再到银幕后面等我的信号
Then take your place behind the
screen and wait for my cue.
然后就把戏院烧掉
Then burn it down.
请就座
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Take your seats.
电影即将开始放映
The show is about to begin.
各位，请就座，即将开始放映
Everybody, please take your seats.
The show is about to begin.
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
待会见
We'll see you later.
且慢
(HANS SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
不远
Not so fast.
来杯香槟...
A glass of champagne...
...向《祖国的荣耀》致敬
...to toast ''Nation's Pride.''
我能私下跟你谈谈吗？
My fraulein, may l have a word
with you in private?
没问题
Certainly.
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)
失陪一下
Excuse us.
请坐
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Have a seat, my fraulein.
让我来
May l?
米敏优小姐让我在她办公室...
Mademoiselle Mimieux allowed me...
...设立指挥中心
...to set up camp in her office
for the time being.
让我看看你的脚
Let me see your foot.
你说什么？
l beg your pardon?
把你的脚放在我大腿上
Put your foot in my lap.
汉斯，你让我很害羞
Hans, you embarrass me.
请你伸进我大衣的右口袋...
Could you please reach into
the right pocket of my coat...
...给我看你拿到什么
...and give me what you find in there.
让我来
May l?
美国人是怎么说来着？
“鞋子合脚，你就得穿上”
What's that American expression?
''lf the shoe fits, you must wear it.''
现在你想怎样？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
What now, Colonel?
穿白色晚礼服的家伙
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
The guy in the white smoking Jacket.
操你奶奶的，臭玻璃
去你的！
ALDO: Fucking shithead.
Faggot fuck. Fuck you!
一群他妈的猪头
Bunch of shithead fuck.
你也去死吧！
Fuck you, too!
该死的臭纳粹，狗娘养的
把你们的臭手拿开
Goddamn Nazi farts, sons of bitches!
Get your hands off me.
全身骚味的臭德国佬...
去你的！放手！
You fucking bratwurst-smelling...
God damn you! Get off!
聪明
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Clever.
我告诉元首观众已经入席
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l informed the Fuhrer that the
audience has taken their seats.
他应该随时就会到
He should arrive any minute.
谢谢你，汉斯
Thank you, Hans.
你们这些臭德国佬...
ALDO: You Jerry-banging,
Limburg-smelling...
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
放开他
Let go.
就像电影台词一样
我猜你就是艾多雷恩中尉吧？
As Stanley said to Livingstone,
Lieutenant Aldo Raine, l presume?
汉斯蓝达
Hans Landa.
你风光了好一阵子，艾多
You've had a nice long run, Aldo.
最后还是落到党卫军的手中
Alas, you're now in the hands of the SS.
其实是落到我的手中
My hands to be exact.
大家都等了很久想教训你
And they've been waiting a long time
to touch you.
逮到你退缩了
Caught you flinching.
看你敢不敢再碰我
ALDO: Touch me again,
Kraut-burger.
-尤特维奇？
-是你吗，中尉？
ALDO: Utivich?
UTlVlCH: ls that you, Lieutenant?
是
ALDO: Yeah.
你知道唐尼怎么了吗？
UTlVlCH: Do you know
what happened to Donny?
欧玛呢？
Omar?
-还有那个女的？
-我不知道
-The woman?
-ALDO: No, l do not.
告诉我，要是换我坐在那里
Tell me, Aldo,
if l were sitting where you're sitting,
你会饶过我吗？
would you show me mercy?
不会
Nope.
英文不是有句鞋子和脚的俗语？
What is that English expression
about shoes and feet?
“左右脚的鞋子穿反了”
我正好也想到这句
''Looks like the shoe is on the other foot.''
Yeah, l was Just thinking that.
你们下去吧
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
You may leave us.
不过在外面看守
But stay alert outside.
你就是阿帕契人艾多
So you're Aldo the Apache.
-你就是犹太人终结者
-我是个侦探
-So you're The Jew Hunter.
-l'm a detective.
很高竿的侦探
A damn good detective.
找人是我的专长
Finding people is my specialty,
我专门替纳粹找人
so naturally, l worked for the Nazis
finding people.
有些是犹太人，但犹太人终结者？
And, yes, some of them were Jews.
But Jew Hunter?
那只是无聊的称号
Just a name that stuck.
不过你得承认很好记
Well, you do have to admit, it is catchy.
你能管敌人替你取的绰号吗？
Do you control the nicknames
your enemies bestow on you?
阿帕契人艾多和小矮子
Aldo the Apache and the Little Man?
小矮子，什么意思？
What do you mean the Little Man?
德军替你取的绰号
Germans' nickname for you.
我的绰号是小矮子？
The Germans' nickname for me
is the Little Man?
容我说一句话
看到你这么高让我吓一跳
And as if to make my point, l'm a little
surprised how tall you were in real life.
你个子不高，但并不是侏儒
l mean, you're a little fellow,
but not circus-midget little,
完全不符合你的绰号
as your reputation would suggest.
我的手下呢？
Where's my men?
布莉姬范海慕丝玛克呢？
Where's Bridget von Hammersmark?
姑且说，她得到该有的惩罚
Well, let's Just say,
she got what she deserved.
当你买通她这种双面间谍
And when you purchase friends like
Bridget von Hammersmark,
只能说便宜没好货
you get what you pay for.
至于你的麻吉们
唐诺维兹中士和欧玛一等兵...
Now as far as your paeSanoS,
Sergeant Donowitz and Private Omar...
你怎么知道我们的名字？
How you know our names?
艾多中尉
Lieutenant Aldo,
如果你以为我不会拷问
if you don't think l wouldn't interrogate
额头被你刻上纳粹记号的人
every single one of your
swastika-marked survivors,
我们就没有我期待的互相尊重
we simply aren't operating on the level
of mutual respect l assumed.
我猜没有吧
No, l guess not.
回到你的两名意大利破坏分子
Well, back to the whereabouts
of your two ltalian saboteurs.
目前为止
As of this moment,
他们都应该还坐在座位上吧
both Omar and Donowitz should be sitting
in the very seats we left them in.
我记得是0023和0024号座位
Double-zero 23 and double-zero 24,
if my memory serves.
他们的脚踝还绑着炸药
随时都能引爆
Explosives still around their ankles,
still ready to explode.
至于你的任务
有些人会称之为恐怖行动
And your mission,
some would call a terrorist plot,
目前仍在进行中
as of this moment, is still a go.
这真是好消息
接下来呢？请他们看卡通？
That's a pretty exciting story.
What's next? Eliza on Ice?
但是
However,
我只要拿起电话听筒通知戏院
你的计划就泡汤
all l have to do is pick up
this phone right here,
inform the cinema, and your plan is kaput.
“如果”他们还在，还活着
真的是“如果”
lf they're still here, and if they're still alive,
and that's one big if,
你想抓他们，炸药就会引爆
there ain't no way you're going to take
them boys without setting off them bombs.
我毫不怀疑
l have no doubt.
有些德国人会死
也会破坏这美好的一夜
And, yes, some Germans will die.
Yes, it will ruin the evening.
你毁了戈培尔光荣的一刻
And, yes, Goebbels will be
very, very, very mad at you
他会对你超不爽的
for what you've done to his big night.
不过你杀不了他和希特勒
But you won't get Hitler,
you won't get Goebbels,
也杀不了戈林和鲍曼
you won't get Goring,
and you won't get Bormann.
要杀死这四个人才能结束战争
And you need all four to end the war.
要是我不拿起电话听筒
But if l don't pick up this phone right here,
你搞不好就能杀死他们
you may very well get all four.
如果你杀死他们
今晚战争就会
And if you get all four, you end the war
结束
tonight.
所以各位
So, gentlemen,
让我们讨论今晚结束战争的可能
let's discuss the prospect
of ending the war tonight.
照我看来
So, the way l see it,
我的行动能决定希特勒的生死
since Hitler's death or possible rescue
rests solely on my reaction,
如果我坐视不管
if l do nothing,
他的死也等于是我造成的
你同意吧？
it's as if l'm causing his death even more
than yourselves. Wouldn't you agree?
我猜是吧
l guess so.
你呢，尤特维奇？
How about you, Utivich?
我猜也是
l guess so, too.
各位，我并不想杀死希特勒
戈培尔、戈林和鲍曼
Gentlemen, l have no intention
of killing Hitler and killing Goebbels
and killing Goring and killing Bormann,
更不会拱手把胜利让给盟军
not to mention winning the war
single-handedly for the Allies,
然后发现自己站在犹太法庭
only later to find myself standing
before a Jewish tribunal.
如果你们今晚想赢得战争
lf you want to win the war tonight,
我们就得谈谈条件
we have to make a deal.
什么样的条件？
What kind of deal?
你无权决定的条件
The kind you wouldn't
have the authority to make.
不过这场行动一定有指挥官
However, l'm sure this mission of yours
has a commanding officer.
一位将军
A general.
我打赌...
l'm betting for...
我猜应该是战略情报局
OSS would be my guess.
宝“狗”
That's a bingo!
是不是这样说？宝“狗”？
ls that the way you say it? ''That's a bingo.''
是“果”不是“狗”
You Just say, ''Bingo.''
宝果，真好玩
Bingo! How fun.
我离题了，我们说到哪儿？
谈条件
But l digress. Where were we?
Yeah! Make a deal.
那里有一台效能很强的无线电
Over there is a very capable
two-way radio and sitting behind it
还有一名优秀的通讯官赫曼
is a more than capable radio operator
named Hermann.
帮我联络盟军的将领
Get me someone
on the other end of that radio
他有权力核准我的
with the power of the pen to authorize my,
这么说吧，有条件的投降
let's call it, the terms
of my conditional surrender.
如果这么说比较好听
lf that tastes better going down.
我来的地方...
You know, where l'm from...
到底是哪里？
Yeah? Where is that exactly?
美丽谷，田纳西州
Maynardville, Tennessee.
我卖过不少私酒
l've done my share of bootlegging.
如果你干的是
联邦政府说的非法勾当
Up there, if you engage in what the federal
government calls illegal activity,
而我们贩卖私酒
but what we call Just a man trying
to make a living for his family
只是为了养家活口的话
你就得随时提高警觉
selling moonshine liquor,
it behooves oneself to keep his wits.
长话短说，听起来太好的事
Long story short, we hear
a story too good to be true,
其实并不好
it ain't.
换作是我，我大概也会这么说
Sitting in your chair,
l would probably say the same thing,
而且绝大多数的时候
你说的完全没错
and 999.999 times out of a million,
you would be correct.
不过在历史的滚轮下
But in the pages of history,
every once in a while,
偶尔命运之神会伸出手来
fate reaches out and extends its hand.
历史课本会怎么写？
What shall the history books read?
我求你，我们一定要炸毁钟塔
MAN.; I implore you.
we muSt deStroy that tower.
中士，那栋钟塔...
Sarge, that tower...
不能炸毁钟塔！
MAN.; The tower StandS!
口香糖？
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Gum?
时候到了
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
lt's time.
我去封锁大门，再到银幕后面
l should go lock the auditorium and
take my place behind the screen.
当世人记载今晚的军事史
HANS: So when the military history
of this night is written,
我将是电影院行动的一分子
it will be recorded that l
was part of Operation Kino
从一开始我就是双面间谍
from the very beginning as a double agent.
我伪装成党卫军上校做的一切
Anything l've done in my guise
as an SS Colonel
都受到战略情报局的认可
was sanctioned by the OSS
as a necessary evil
全是为了掩护我的身分
to establish my cover with the Germans.
是我把雷恩中尉的炸药
And it was my placement
of Lieutenant Raine's dynamite
放在希特勒和戈培尔的包厢
确定能把他们炸死
in Hitler and Goebbels' opera box
that assured their demise.
我告诉元首观众已经入席
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l informed the Fuhrer that the
audience has taken their seats.
他应该随时就会到
He should arrive any minute.
谢谢你，汉斯
Thank you, Hans.
最后那部分是真的
By the way, that last part is actually true.
我要全额的军职人员退抚金
以及按照我官阶的福利
l want my full military pension
and benefits under my proper rank.
我要因为协助推翻第三帝国
l want to receive
the Congressional Medal of Honor
获颁国会荣誉勋章
for my invaluable assistance
in the toppling of the Third Reich.
其实我要这次行动每个成员
ln fact, l want all the members
of Operation Kino
都获颁国会荣誉勋章
to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honor.
不用说，我要成为美国公民
Full citizenship for myself.
Well, that goes without saying.
我要美国政府
And l would like
the United States of America
替我在南塔克特岛置产
to purchase property for me
on Nantucket lsland
因为我加速纳粹党暴政的瓦解
as a reward for all
the countless lives l've saved
拯救了无数人命
by bringing the tyranny
of the National Socialist Party
藉以奖赏我的功劳
您都记下来了吗？
to a swifter-than-imagined end.
Do you have all that, sir?
我也很期待能和您面对面
l look forward to seeing you
face to face as well, sir.
雷恩中尉？他在这里
Lieutenant Raine? Right here.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
蓝达上校会把你和尤特维奇
以战俘身分押上卡车
GENERAL.; Colonel Landa will put you
and Private Utivich in a truck aS priSonerS.
然后他和通讯官会上车
开到我们的防线
Then he and hiS radio operator will
get in the truck and drive to our lineS.
一旦跨越防线
蓝达上校和手下会向你投降
Upon croSSing our lineS, Colonel Landa
and hiS man will Surrender to you.
你要接手驾驶卡车
You will then take over driving of the truck
把他们带来做简报，了解吗？
and bring them Straight to me for debriefing.
IS that clear, Lieutenant?
了解，长官
Yes, sir.
通话完毕
Over and out.
戈培尔博士，我想出去一下
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Herr Dr. Goebbels, excuse me.
Could l go out for a moment?
我完全能理解
去吧，电影结束后见
Perfectly understandable, my boy.
You go now,
and we'll see you after the show.
哪位？
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Who is it?
弗德列克！
Fredrick!
该死
Shit.
你是戏院经理吗？我要退钱
Are you the manager of this cinema?
l want my money back.
男主角演得烂透了
That actor in the movie stinks.
你跑来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我来看你呀
l came to visit you.
你没看到我在忙吗？
Can't you see how busy l am?
那就让我帮忙
Then allow me to lend an assist.
这不好笑，你不能进来
Fredrick, it's not funny, you can't be here.
这是你的首映会，快回去吧
This is your premiere,
you need to be out there with them.
平常来说，你说得对
Normally, you would be right.
我对我拍的其它电影...
And for all the other films l do...
...绝对会以高昂气势撑到底
...l intend to endure evenings like tonight,
in the proper spirit.
但是，事实是...
However, the fact remains...
...这部电影改编自我的经历
...this film is based on my military exploits.
而我的经历包括杀死很多人
And in this case,
my exploits consisted of killing many men.
现在放映的这个部分...
Consequently, the part of
the film that's playing now...
...我真的很不想看
...l don't like watching this part.
-很抱歉，弗德列克...
-所以...
-l am sorry, Fredrick, but...
-So, l thought...
...我就想上来尽全力...
...l'd come up here and do what l do best...
...来烦你
...annoy you.
从你的表情看来，我很成功
And from the look on your face,
it would appear l haven't lost my touch.
你真的很习惯受到奉承...
Are you so used to
the Nazis kissing your ass...
...忘了“不”的意思吗？
...you've forgotten what the word
''no'' means?
不...你不能进来
No...you can't be here!
走开
Now go away!
弗德列克，你弄痛我了
Fredrick, you hurt me.
很高兴知道你至少有感觉
Well, it's nice to know
you can feel something.
就算只是身体的痛楚
Even if it's Just physical pain.
我不是那种轻易放弃的人
l'm not a man you say, ''go away'' to.
意大利有三百多具尸体能作证
There's over three hundred dead bodies
in ltaly,
that if they could, would testify to that!
我为你做了这么多...
After what l've done for you...
...你却毫不尊重我
...you disrespect me at your peril!
把门锁上
Lock the door.
什么？
What?
把门锁上
Lock the door.
我们时间不多
We don't have much time.
要干嘛？
Time for what?
(SlGHS)
算了！
Forget it!
不...不...等等
--No, no, no...wait.
你要我...把门锁上？
You want me to...lock the door?
要我说几百遍，对啦
For the fifty-seventh time, yes.
我杀了他，你离警卫还有30英尺
When l kill that guy,
you got 30 feet to get to that guard.
-你办得到吗？
-我非办到不行
-Can you do it?
-l have to.
来杯香槟？
Champagne?
太赞了，太精采了！
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Extraordinary my dear, simply extraordinary!
这是你至今最好的作品
This is your finest film yet.
多谢夸奖，元首
Thank you, my Fuhrer.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谁要向德国传送讯息？
who wantS to Send a meSSage to Germany?
我要向德国传送一个讯息
I have a meSSage for Germany.
你们全都会死翘翘
That you are all going to die.
够了！关掉！
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
Enough! Stop it!
把放映机关掉！
Turn off the proJector!
我要你们仔细看
要杀死你们的犹太人的巨脸
And I want you to look deep into the face
of the Jew who'S going to do it!
我不懂，这不是我的电影
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
l don't know what's going on.
That does not belong in my movie!
马瑟，把戏院烧掉吧
Marcel, burn it down.
是，苏珊娜
Oui, Shosanna.
我叫苏珊娜德瑞芙斯
My name iS ShoSanna DreyfuS,
这就是
and thiS iS the face
犹太人复仇的巨脸
of JewiSh vengeance.
美军防线到了，上校
(SPEAKlNG GERMAN)
These are the American lines, Colonel sir.
太好了，赫曼
Excellent, Hermann.
解开他们的手铐
HANS: Hermann, uncuff them.
我正式向你投降，雷恩中尉
l'm officially surrendering myself
over to you, Lieutenant Raine.
我们是你的战俘
We're your prisoners.
我的刀子呢？
How about my knife?
谢谢你，上校
Thank you very much, Colonel.
把上校的双手铐起来
Utivich, cuff the Colonel's hands
behind his back.
真的有这必要吗？
ls that really necessary?
这是一定要的
l'm a slave to appearances.
剥了他的头皮
Scalp Hermann.
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
你做了什么？
What have you done?
你的将军说好不会杀他！
l made a deal with your general
for that man's life!
没错，不过他们只需要你
Yeah, they made that deal. But they don't
give a fuck about him. They need you.
你会因此被枪决
You'll be shot for this!
才怪，只会被臭骂一顿而已
我从小被骂到大
Nah, l don't think so. More like chewed out.
l've been chewed out before.
我们听到你和将军谈的条件
You know, Utivich and myself heard
that deal you made with the brass.
今晚就结束战争？
End the war tonight?
我也会答应你的条件
l'd make that deal.
你呢？你会答应吗？
How about you, Utivich?
You make that deal?
-当然会
-我不怪你，条件真的很好
-l'd make that deal.
-l don't blame you. Damn good deal.
至于你替自己争取的福利
And that pretty little nest
you feathered for yourself.
如果你肯烧死德军的高层领导
Well, if you're willing to barbecue
the whole High Command,
搞不好是很值得考虑
l suppose that's worth
certain considerations.
不过我有一个问题
But l do have one question.
当你到了南塔克特岛
When you get to your little place
on Nantucket lsland,
一定会脱掉帅气的党卫军制服
l imagine you are going to take off
that handsome-looking SS uniform of yours.
对吧？
Ain't you?
我就知道
That's what l thought.
这我可不能接受
Now, that l can't abide.
你呢？你能接受吗？
How about you, Utivich, can you abide it?
绝对不能
Not one damn bit, sir.
要是照我的方法
l mean, if l had my way,
你这辈子都得穿着那套军服
you'd wear that goddamn uniform
for the rest of your pecker-sucking life.
不过我知道很不实际
But l'm aware that ain't practical.
你总得把它脱掉
l mean, at some point,
you're going to have to take it off.
所以呢
So,
我要给你一个脱不掉的记号
l'm going to give you
a little something you can't take off.
你知道吗，尤特维奇？
You know something, Utivich?
这应该会是我的旷世巨作
l think this Just might be my masterpiece.